<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Come to the Dark Side! We have a whole bunch of Cookiecutters!</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/europython-2015/come-to-the-dark-side-we-have-a-whole-bunch-of-cookiecutters.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Raphael Pierzina - Come to the Dark Side! We have a whole bunch of Cookiecutters!
[EuroPython 2015]
[23 July 2015]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(This talk is intended for intermediate-level participants who have a
basic understanding of the Python language and contains quotes from
Darth Vader that some attendees may find hilarious)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing a Python script from scratch is fairly easy and you get on
with very little boilerplate code in general. However starting a new
Python project can be tiring if you decide to stick to best practices
and plan on submitting it to PyPI. It requires great diligence and
occasionally gets pretty cumbersome if you start new tools on a
regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="you-underestimate-the-power-of-a-good-template"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;You underestimate the power of a good template&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why not just use a template for it? Cookiecutter is a CLI tool written
in pure Python that enables you to do so. Not only is it working for
Python code, but also markdown formats and even other programming
languages. We will talk about the ideas behind Cookiecutter and go
over how you can create your very own template, so you and others can
benefit from your experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to briefly go into the technologies used and how you can
get involved in the Cookiecutter GitHub project. There are already
plenty of Cookiecutter templates, or Cookiecutters as we call them,
available online. Most of them target Python projects, but others can
be used to create C++, LaTeX or Javascript projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ability to destroy a planet is insignificant next to the power of
Cookiecutter.
----------------------------------------------------------------------
-------------&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will show you how to use Cookiecutter and highlight some of the
amazing templates created by the community. More importantly we will
create a Cookiecutter template from scratch using the example of a
simple Kivy app and make use of advanced features such as post-gen
hooks, copy-without-render and templates in context values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally I will recommend resources on how to follow up on this talk
and how to get in touch in case of any queries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitHub: [&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/hackebrot][1"&gt;https://github.com/hackebrot][1&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter: [&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/hackebrot][2"&gt;https://twitter.com/hackebrot][2&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blog: [&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.hackebrot.de/][3"&gt;http://www.hackebrot.de/][3&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/hackebrot"&gt;https://github.com/hackebrot&lt;/a&gt;
[2]: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/hackebrot"&gt;https://twitter.com/hackebrot&lt;/a&gt;
[3]: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.hackebrot.de/"&gt;http://www.hackebrot.de/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Raphael Pierzina</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-03:europython-2015/come-to-the-dark-side-we-have-a-whole-bunch-of-cookiecutters.html</guid></item><item><title>Pytest 3.0</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/europython-2016/pytest-30.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Raphael Pierzina - Pytest 3.0
[EuroPython 2016]
[21 July 2016]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/pytest-30"&gt;https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/pytest-30&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New features of pytest's upcoming major version 3.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Breaking changes and other important information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recap of the first developer sprint in June, 2016&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thank you notes to all who have contributed to the fundraiser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pytest is a mature testing framework for Python that is developed by a
thriving and ever-growing community of volunteers. Following the
principle of &amp;quot;no API is the best API&amp;quot; it uses plain assert statements
and regular Python comparisons. Writing tests with pytest requires
little to no boilerplate code and powerful features allow easy
parametrization and intelligent test selection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will have an in-depth look at new features of pytest
3.0 and live demo possible use cases. We will also learn about
important bugfixes and other enhancements of the upcoming major
release. Backwards-incompatible changes will be addressed and changes
made to the documentation will be highlighted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are already familiar with pytest, you will be happy to hear
about significant improvements of the fixture and hook system but also
what's in store for a better integration with tox, an important tool
that allows testing across different Python versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In June, 2016 more than 25 Pythonistas from around the globe gather in
Freiburg, Germany to work on the release and set the path for future
developments of the core framework. This is a big step forward for the
project made posssible by a fundraiser that reached 108% of it's
initial goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will share our experiences from the developer sprint while they are
still fresh and explain why these events are incredibly important for
a community and give advice on how to organize your own.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Raphael Pierzina</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-04:europython-2016/pytest-30.html</guid></item></channel></rss>