<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_camilla-montonen.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2015-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Simulating and visualising commuter flow through the London Underground</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pydata-paris-2015/simulating-and-visualising-commuter-flow-through.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Camilla Montonen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-04-14:pydata-paris-2015/simulating-and-visualising-commuter-flow-through.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every year the London Tube transports about 1.3 billion commuters. With
multiple intersecting lines, the daily functioning of the London Tube
network poses many interesting questions: What effects do severe delays
on the Piccadilly Line have on passengers taking the Northern Line? What
is the shortest path from station x to station y? How does overcrowding
on one station affect its neighbouring stations? These are but a few
examples of the many questions one can start to investigate using two
Python libraries: graph­tool for manipulating and analysing graphs and
bokeh for visualizing and streaming “live” data from simulations. In
this talk, I will briefly show how one can transform structures such as
the London Underground map into programmatic objects that can be
analysed and manipulated using Python. Furthermore, I will show examples
of simulations based on the publicly available data from Transport for
London and illustrate how simulations can be used to glean insight on
the large scale behaviour of a complex system. Last but not least, I
hope to illustrate how the bokeh server can be leveraged to create
“real­time” visualizations of simulations.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>