<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_daniel-chen.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Introduction to Pandas</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pydata-carolinas-2016/introduction-to-pandas.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Daniel Chen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-14:pydata-carolinas-2016/introduction-to-pandas.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This tutorial aims to expose future data analysis with the Python
Pandas library. The tutorial is meant for absolute beginners to Pandas
and Python as a programming language. We will begin with loading
tabular data and various ways to calculate summary statistics and
visualize data. Next, we will learn various ways to join multiple
datasets, and how we can work with missing values etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the tutorial is to expose users to Pandas for data
analysis and move users into a more reproducible analysis workflow
compared to spreadsheet programs. The tutorial will begin with loading
in tabular data and various ways to view columns and rows of data. The
initial part of the tutorial will show users how to load in data and
quickly create descriptive statistical plots. Next, we will cover more
of pandas internal data structures. This will cover some fundamental
knowledge about Python as a programming language, mainly object
methods. Finally, before showing users basic data cleaning examples,
we will cover data visualizations using matplotlib, seaborn, and
pandas itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next section of the tutorial will show learners how to assemble
and merge multiple datasets, and how to work with missing values.
Lastly, before we get to fitting models, I will go over how to recode
variables for analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main purpose is to show users how to use Pandas, and not how to
fit machine learning models. However, I show a simple model at the end
so users see how data cleaning and analysis all fit together in a
workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Python useRs</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pydata-dc-2016/python-users.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Daniel Chen</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-08:pydata-dc-2016/python-users.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData DC 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the most recent IEEE language rankings, R is now the 5th most popular language. It is the only domain specific language in the top 5, behind the general-purpose languages C, Java, Python, and C++, respectively. It is common for data science teams to work in multiple languages and for the Pythonista, a working knowledge in R is useful for collaboration, analysis, and performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may be better to extend a simple analysis in R than passing around CSV files. Even worse, there might be a new analysis package that only exists in R, or certain bits infrastructure are already implemented in R and it needs to incorporate a bit of Python analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>