<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Deploy your Python Application Without Getting Owned</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2016/deploy-your-python-application-without-getting-owned.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With severe security vulnerabilities on the rise, it’s critical for
Python developers to understand how to protect their applications.
Unattended upgrades, automated TLS certificate provisioning, enhanced
web security, and other measures can significantly reduce the attack
surface of the systems upon which our applications run.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Justin Mayer</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-05:pycon-ireland-2016/deploy-your-python-application-without-getting-owned.html</guid></item><item><title>DevOps Security — Protect Your Application From Being Owned</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-italia-2015/devops-security-protect-your-application-from-b.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition to outlining strategies for proper configuration of
unattended security updates, this talk briefly covers how to maintain
the security of Docker container environments, where the above
strategies generally do not apply. In such environments, an entirely
different approach and workflow is usually required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Heartbleed, Shellshock, POODLE, GHOST… With severe security
vulnerabilities on the rise, how can developers protect the systems used
to deploy their applications? Unattended package upgrades can help, but
only if they are properly set up and monitored. Some of the challenges
include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;many popular virtual private server (VPS) providers do not install or
enable automatic security updates in their OS images&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“unattended-upgrades” on Debian-based systems installs automatic
security updates but does not actually enable them, potentially
putting unsuspecting users at risk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some security updates (e.g., kernel-level) require a server reboot to
take effect, and yet users often don’t realize this until the next
time they log in, resulting in a system that is vulnerable in the
interim&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Justin Mayer</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-06-09:pycon-italia-2015/devops-security-protect-your-application-from-b.html</guid></item></channel></rss>