<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_stephanie-kim.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Investigating User Experience with Natural Language Analysis</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pydata-seattle-2015/investigating-user-experience-with-natural-language-analysis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stephanie Kim</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-25:pydata-seattle-2015/investigating-user-experience-with-natural-language-analysis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk focuses on the methodology and intent of studying feedback form data using Python tools and libraries for natural language processing and machine learning analysis. I will discuss potential trouble areas of starting such a project from scratch from a developer’s perspective. This will include the type of analysis that might be helpful in discerning user experience and what analysis that you run, but might end up tossing out at the end due to lack of insight on your data. For instance, what is the value of running a K-Means cluster analysis and does it offer substantial actionable insights for textual content? And how much data do you need to pre-label for a training set for a Naïve Bayes Classification in order for it to be accurate? My intent is that people will walk away learning the basics of textual analysis and become motivated to help their users succeed in whatever tasks they are trying to accomplish through finding potential points of friction and even issues that spring up from changes in the design. This talk will be for developers or marketers who don’t have a lot or any experience in data analysis or machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Triaging Feedback Form Data</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pydata-dc-2016/triaging-feedback-form-data.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Stephanie Kim</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-09:pydata-dc-2016/triaging-feedback-form-data.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData DC 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will cover how to use predictive modeling on unstructured text data including feedback form, social media or chat message data to triage issues in order to prevent future problems with a service, platform or user interface using NLP techniques in Python and R.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Companies gain useful insights about their users from feedback form and other unstructured text data including live chat messages. Even though they are read and responded to, often such data is ignored when thinking about larger scale trend analysis and this can result in missed insight about how users react to a product or service. Sometimes analysis is being done by looking at changes in user sentiment or other heuristics, however it could be taken a step further by applying predictive modeling in attempt to recognize areas that need more attention and support. While you can use predictive modeling on network and log data, that is looking at how the hardware is handling your users requests, not how it's being perceived by users. By predicting areas where users are having difficulty whether it's with the UI or with the platform's response time you can triage these areas of concern to prevent future cases of negative perception. This talk will cover how to utilize common NLP tools used to gather and process the features in Python then will use R to perform trend analysis and predictive modeling then use the results to triage what areas should be focused on in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Data"></category></entry></feed>