<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_guillem-duran.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Per Shaolin ad Astra</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-es-2016/per-shaolin-ad-astra.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Guillem Durán</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-09:pycon-es-2016/per-shaolin-ad-astra.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will show how it is possible to build an interactive 3D model of the solar system using the python packages shaolin and poliastro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At EuroPython Juan Luis Cano asked for a 3D visualization module for poliastro, and now we are finally presenting the first version of the poliastro 3D models build using plotly and vpython.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will review the data presented at EuroPython 2016 with an interactive model of the solar system for representing planets and its orbits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Materials available at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/Guillem-db/PyconEs-2016"&gt;https://github.com/Guillem-db/PyconEs-2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://2016.es.pycon.org/"&gt;http://2016.es.pycon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Interactive data Kung Fu with Shaolin</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/europython-2016/interactive-data-kung-fu-with-shaolin.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Guillem Duran</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-05:europython-2016/interactive-data-kung-fu-with-shaolin.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Guillem Duran - Interactive data Kung Fu with Shaolin
[EuroPython 2016]
[18 July 2016]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/interactive-data-kung-fu-with-shaolin"&gt;https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/interactive-data-kung-fu-with-shaolin&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Notebooks come alive when interactive widgets are used”, but
programming complex applications that rely entirely on widgets may end
up being a painful and frustrating process. Shaolin is a new python
project that aims to provide a framework for building interactive
complex dashboards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read in The Project Jupyter web page that “Notebooks come
alive when interactive widgets are used”, but programming complex
applications that rely entirely on widgets may end up being a painful
and frustrating process. Shaolin is a new python project that aims to
provide a framework for building interactive complex dashboards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shaolin provides all the basic tools for building complex interactive
data analysis applications using the pydata ecosystem. Arbitrary code
can be embedded into a Dashboard -a class that works as a “black box”
that allows to easily define a GUI based on the ipywidgets package- to
process any data in any form and then let you interactively define how
to plot it using automatically generated widgets. Hierarchical
combinations of Dashboards can be arranged then to build more complex
applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk is divided in two sections. First one introduce the framework
and its main features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Custom syntax for defining widgets in a simplified way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dashboards: Syntax rules and capabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Combining Dashboards to build complex applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interactive plot creation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integration with pydata.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second section will show how this framework can be used to analyse
real data using Dashboards without writing any code. I will show how
to transform market data time series into graphs using pandas and
networkx, then plot it interactively using bokeh and Vpython.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>