<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Creativity and AI: Deep Neural Nets "Going Wild"</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2017/creativity-and-ai-deep-neural-nets-going-wild.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Amsterdam 2017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We live in times, where science fiction authors are struggling to keep up with reality. This talk will make sense of the explosion of research and experiments that deal with creativity and A.I. and take you through the wonderful trippy world of neural nets &amp;quot;going wild&amp;quot; and show some of the exciting possibilities new technologies offer for making us all more creative, more of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We live in times, where science fiction authors are struggling to keep up with reality. This talk will make sense of the explosion of research and experiments that deal with creativity and A.I. and take you through the wonderful trippy world of neural nets &amp;quot;going wild&amp;quot; with their dancing moves, freestyle raps, impressionist paintings. and show some of the exciting possibilities new technologies offer for creative use and explorations of human-machine interaction, where the main theorem is &amp;quot;augmentation, not automation&amp;quot;. The talk will particularly focus on &amp;quot;generative&amp;quot; models, and show the python fanatic how to make your move with these particular forms of Deep Neural Nets, to then finish with an &amp;quot;experiment&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Roelof Pieters</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-04-08:pydata-amsterdam-2017/creativity-and-ai-deep-neural-nets-going-wild.html</guid></item><item><title>Deep Learning and Deep Data Science</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-se-2015/deep-learning-and-deep-data-science.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deep Learning, anyone who has followed machine learning over the past
years has heard it. In this talk I will go past the hype and show what
deep learning actually means and how one goes about solving complex
machine learning task with a minimum amount of code, with the help of
theano, an amazing python library for deep learning. I will show
examples from my own research in language and vision, and hope to show
that Deep Learning is not only fun, but also not as difficult as one
might expect.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Roelof Pieters</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-25:pycon-se-2015/deep-learning-and-deep-data-science.html</guid></item></channel></rss>