<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_benno-luthiger.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2011-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>The political implications of having fun (while programming open source)</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/the-political-implications-of-having-fun-while-p.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Benno Luthiger</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-24:europython-2011/the-political-implications-of-having-fun-while-p.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Benno Luthiger - 23 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Spaghetti&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are the implications for the society if people enjoy their work,
because this work is perceived as rewarding by itself? It is this
question that occupies me since I have finished my Ph.D. research about
the motivation of open source programmers. In my research, I have been
able to show that fun is an important driver for open source
programmers. Moreover, fun plays an important role not only for
hobbyists, but for developers who are paid for their work too (open or
closed source).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These findings contrast with the traditional efforts of leftist parties
and labor unions. For those political organizations, labor is perceived
as compulsion and exploitation and, therefore, people have to be
liberated from labor. The resulting political praxis is to send people
into retirement as soon as possible and, on the other hand, to make the
life for unemployed people carefree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is the software developers‘ world a little Shangri-La, apart from the
real world, delineated by the leftist parties, or is the open source
model generalizable? What happens with the values generated through the
labor if the work as such is rewarding? The open source mode of
production is part of our modern reality and in my presentation I would
like to consider this big reality from the perspective of open source.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>