<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Making CPython Fast Using Trace-based Optimisations</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/making-cpython-fast-using-trace-based-optimisatio.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Mark Shannon - 24 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Lasagne&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;CPython can be made faster by implementing the sort of optimizations
used in the PyPy VM, and in my HotPy VM. All the necessary changes can
be made without modifying the language or the API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CPython VM can be modified to support optimizations by adding an
effective garbage collector and by separating the virtual-machine state
from the real- machine state (like Stackless).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Optimizations can be implemented incrementally. Since almost all of the
optimizations are implemented in the interpreter, all hardware platforms
can benefit. JIT compiler(s) can then be added for common platforms
(intel, ARM, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information see &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://hotpy.blogspot.com/"&gt;http://hotpy.blogspot.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mark Shannon</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-13:europython-2011/making-cpython-fast-using-trace-based-optimisatio.html</guid><category>cpython</category><category>jit</category><category>pypy</category><category>vm</category></item><item><title>HotPy (2) - A High Performance Binary-Compatible Virtual Machine for Python</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/europython-2012/hotpy-2-a-high-performance-binary-compatible.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2012] Mark Shannon - 5 JULY 2012 in &amp;quot;Track Lasagne&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;HotPy (2) is a new interpreter for Python. It is binary compatible with
CPython and reuses CPython’s object and module implementations. The core
interpreter is new and uses many of the techniques developed during the
1990s and 2000s plus a technique developed during my PhD. Once the first
stage of the optimisation chain is completed (May or June), HotPy is
expected to be between 2 and 3 times as fast as CPython. It will
probably never be as fast as PyPy, but it might be possible to get
close. During the talk I will explain how it works (with lots of
pictures), and how it compares to CPython and PyPy. I will also discuss
whether the techniques used in HotPy would be suitable for Jython and
IronPython.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mark Shannon</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-06:europython-2012/hotpy-2-a-high-performance-binary-compatible.html</guid></item></channel></rss>