<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_oliver-braun.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2015-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Multibody Simulation using sympy, scipy and vpython</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/europython-2015/multibody-simulation-using-sympy-scipy-and-vpython.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Oliver Braun</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-07:europython-2015/multibody-simulation-using-sympy-scipy-and-vpython.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oliver Braun - Multibody Simulation using sympy, scipy and vpython
[EuroPython 2015]
[20 July 2015]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk is about the implementation of multibody simulation in the
scientific python world on the way to a stage usefull for engineering
and educational purposes.
Multibody simulation (MBS) requires two major steps: first the
formulation of the specific mechanical problem. Second step is the
integration of the resulting equations.
For the first step we use the package sympy which is on a very
advanced level to perform symbolic calculation and which supports
already Lagrange's and Kane's formalism. The extensions we made are
such that a complex mechanical setup can be formulated easily with
several lines of python code. The functionality is analogous to well
known MBS-tools, with that you can assemble bodies, joints, forces and
constraints. Also external forces even in a cosimulation model can be
added on top. The second step, the integration is done via ode-
integrators implemented in scipy.
Finally for visual validation the results are visualized with the
vpython package and for further analytics with matplotlib.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusion: not only highly constrained pendulums with many rods and
springs but also driving simulation of passenger cars an be performed
with our new extension using python packages off the shelf.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>