<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Public Python for the greater good</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2016/public-python-for-the-greater-good.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://code4sa.org/"&gt;Code For South Africa&lt;/a&gt; use technology to
facilitate promoting informed decision making for positive social
change. This can mean generally being aware of what's going on, as well
as deep critical research and analysis. We run the civic tech movement
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://codebridge.org.za"&gt;{code}bridge&lt;/a&gt; where people come and hack
together or on their lonesome on civic tech projects. A quick summary
will be given of some outputs of this community in Cape Town and
Ethekwini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll summarise some work we've done using mostly common python tools
for the good of South African society. In particular I'll show how I've
scraped and mirrored a government website on a tight budget at
{code}bridge for better access to public information and seen usage pick
up right after the local elections. We'll also show how a little bit of
tech can empower citizens to hold government to account, and participate
in the governing and development of our infrastructure. How presumably
boring government notices really come to life when made accessible and
personal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is aimed at anyone keen on making a big impact with a little
bit of tech, and interested in improving lives. There are many low
hanging fruit out there where lives can be improved with technology
facilitating the necessary groundwork. I'd like to show you how easy it
is to make an impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a heavily revised version of a talk given at DebConf 2016 with
several new projects matured or launched since.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">JD Bothma</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-06:pycon-za-2016/public-python-for-the-greater-good.html</guid></item></channel></rss>