<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>IPython-Reveal.js Attacks Again, But Now... It Is Alive!</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/ipython-revealjs-attacks-again-but-now-it-is.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently, the IPython Notebook has began to be used for presentations in
several conferences. But, there is not a full-featured and executable
IPython presentation tool available. So, we developed a new
Reveal.js-powered live slideshow extension, designed specifically to be
used directly from the notebook and to be as executable as the notebook
is, and also powered with great features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Detailed Abtract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last years, &lt;strong&gt;IPython&lt;/strong&gt;, a comprehensive environment for
interactive and exploratory computing, has arose as must-have
application to run in the daily scientific &lt;em&gt;work-flow&lt;/em&gt; because provides,
not only an enhanced interactive &lt;strong&gt;Python&lt;/strong&gt; shell (terminal or
qt-based), but also a very popular interactive browser-based
&lt;strong&gt;notebook&lt;/strong&gt; with an unimaginable scope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentation of our research results and the teaching of our
knownledge are very important steps in the scientific research
work-flow, and recently, the &lt;strong&gt;IPython Notebook&lt;/strong&gt; has began to be used
for all kind of oral communications in several conferences, curses,
classes and bootcamps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the fact that we can present our talks with the IPython notebook
itself or through a static &lt;strong&gt;Reveal.js&lt;/strong&gt;-based slideshow powered by
IPython.nbconvert (a tool we presented at SciPy 2013), there is not a
&lt;strong&gt;full-featured&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;executable&lt;/strong&gt; (live) IPython presentation tool
available. So, we developed a new &lt;strong&gt;IPython&lt;/strong&gt;-&lt;strong&gt;Reveal.js&lt;/strong&gt;-powered
&lt;strong&gt;live&lt;/strong&gt; slideshow extension, designed specifically to be used
&lt;strong&gt;directly&lt;/strong&gt; from the IPython notebook and to be as &lt;strong&gt;executable&lt;/strong&gt; as
the notebook is (because deep inside, it is the notebook itself but
rendered with another face), and also powered with a lot of &lt;em&gt;features&lt;/em&gt;
to address the most common tasks performed during the oral presentation
and spreading of our scientific work, such as: main slides and nested
slides, fragments views, transitions, themes and speaker notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To conclude, we have developed a new visualization tool for the
&lt;strong&gt;IPython Notebook&lt;/strong&gt;, suited for the final steps of our scientific
research &lt;em&gt;work-flow&lt;/em&gt;, providing us with, not only an enhanced and new
experience in the oral presentation and communication of our results,
but also with a super-powerful tool at teaching time, helping us to
easily tranfer our concepts and spread our knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see the extension in action in the following video link:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Pc-1FS0l2vg"&gt;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Pc-1FS0l2vg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you can also see the source code of the extension at the following
repository: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://github.com/damianavila/live_reveal"&gt;http://github.com/damianavila/live_reveal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Damia패n Avila</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-13:scipy-2014/ipython-revealjs-attacks-again-but-now-it-is.html</guid></item><item><title>Introducci칩n A Jupyter</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-ar-2014/introduccion-a-jupyter.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dami치n Avila</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-11-28:pycon-ar-2014/introduccion-a-jupyter.html</guid></item><item><title>22. Quantitative Finance Research with Python: Statistical arbitrage.</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2012/22-quantitative-finance-research-with-python-st.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently, many projects have been developed to make Python useful to do
quantitative finance research. We proposed us not only to show you the
integration of these tools to perform time series analysis and modeling,
but also to show you how we can search for cointegrated pairs of asset
and set up a statistical arbitrage strategy - pairs trading - to get
potential profit from financial market.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dami치n Avila</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2012-03-11:pycon-us-2012/22-quantitative-finance-research-with-python-st.html</guid></item></channel></rss>