<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_riona-macnamara.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-05-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Transforming your Documentation Process</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-2016/transforming-your-documentation-process.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-05-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jon Bulava</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-05-22:write-the-docs-2016/transforming-your-documentation-process.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jon Bulava, Ted Hudek, Zach Corleissen, Leon Barnard, Riona MacNamara
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lanyrd.com/2016/writethedocs/sfbztg/"&gt;http://lanyrd.com/2016/writethedocs/sfbztg/&lt;/a&gt;
We had a number of interesting presentations about companies transforming their documentation process. Instead of choosing just one, we asked the speakers to join us on a panel, so that folks can compare and contrast the different approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Documentation, Disrupted: How Two Technical Writers Changed Google Engineering Culture</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-2015/documentation-disrupted-how-two-technical-writers-changed-google-engineering-culture.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-05-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-05-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Riona MacNamara</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-05-19:write-the-docs-2015/documentation-disrupted-how-two-technical-writers-changed-google-engineering-culture.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Riona MacNamara
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lanyrd.com/2015/writethedocs/sdmwxg/"&gt;http://lanyrd.com/2015/writethedocs/sdmwxg/&lt;/a&gt;
Last year, we were inspired to action by a presentation at Write the Docs. This talk will tell the story of what happened next: how, in two quarters, we worked with a small self-forming team of amazing writers and engineers to build a platform in six months is well on the way to becoming a part of the standard Google engineering workflow. We’ll share how that platform transformed our role as technical writers and our relationship with engineering. We’ll cover design and implementation details, but we’ll also talk about our experience - how we learned that being audacious (but not reckless), focused (but open and generous), and unafraid could revitalize our whole approach to work and save us from burnout.
We&amp;amp;#39;ll talk about our ever-growing appetite for disruption: How it changed beyond recognition our relationships with engineers, fellow writers, and senior leadership, making us fall in love again with our roles as documentarians.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>