<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Next Level Testing</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2017/next-level-testing.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unit, functional, and integration tests are great first steps towards
improving the quality of your python project. Ever wonder if there’s
even more you can do? Maybe you've heard of property-based testing,
fuzzing, and mutation testing but you're unsure exactly how they can
help you. In this talk we’ll cover additional types of tests that can
help improve the quality and robustness of your python projects:
property-based testing, fuzz testing, stress testing, long term
reliability testing, and mutation testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll also go beyond just covering what these tests are. For each of the
test types above, I’ll give you real world examples from open source
software that I maintain that shows you the types of bugs each test type
can find. I’ll also show you how you can integrate these tests into your
Travis CI and/or Jenkins environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">James Saryerwinnie</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2017-05-19:pycon-us-2017/next-level-testing.html</guid></item><item><title>Writing Redis in Python with asyncio</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/europython-2016/writing-redis-in-python-with-asyncio.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;James Saryerwinnie - Writing Redis in Python with asyncio
[EuroPython 2016]
[21 July 2016]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/writing-redis-in-python-with-asyncio"&gt;https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/writing-redis-in-python-with-asyncio&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I'll show you how to write redis using asyncio.  You'll
see how you can create a real world application using asyncio by
creating a python port of redis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python has been adding more and more async features to the language.
Starting with asyncio in python 3.4 and including the new async/await
keywords in python 3.5, it's difficult to understand how all these
pieces fit together.  More importantly, it's hard to envision how to
use these new language features in a real world application.  In this
talk we're going to move beyond the basic examples of TCP echo servers
and example servers that can add number together.  Instead I'll show
you a realistic asyncio application.  This application is a port of
redis, a popular data structure server, written in python using
asyncio.  In addition to basic topics such as handling simple redis
commands (GET, SET, APPEND, etc),  we'll look at notifications using
pub/sub, how to implement the MONITOR command, and persistence.  Come
learn how to apply the asyncio library to real world applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">James Saryerwinnie</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-04:europython-2016/writing-redis-in-python-with-asyncio.html</guid></item><item><title>Supporting Everything - Python2/3, Mac/Linux/Windows</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-ca-2013/supporting-everything-python23-maclinuxwind.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There comes a time in the life of a library where it must leave your
machine and find a home in a far away computer. That computer might even
run windows. This talk will show how you can write a library that
supports Linux/Mac/Windows and runs on python 2 and 3.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">James Saryerwinnie</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-08-10:pycon-ca-2013/supporting-everything-python23-maclinuxwind.html</guid><category>talk</category></item></channel></rss>