<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Growing Python with Spreadsheets</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2013/growing-python-with-spreadsheets.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Talk given at PyTexas 2013 by Kojo Idrissa (&amp;#64;Transition).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spreadsheets are the &amp;quot;lingua franca&amp;quot; of data sharing, espeicially within organizations. Outside of technical circles (IT departments, developers, etc), a spreadsheet is still the way most data is analyzed, visualized or reported. While programmers prefer to work with data in another format, many non-programmers either don't have that option or lack the technical accumen to be aware the option exists. As a result, many non-technical people in organizations are forced to use kludgy, limited data analysis tools in spreadsheets. While spreadsheets are good for &lt;em&gt;basic&lt;/em&gt; data visualization (i.e., &amp;quot;What do I have here?&amp;quot;), they lack flexibility and force their users to jump through hoops. &lt;strong&gt;This&lt;/strong&gt; is an opportunity for Python to grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My underlying thesis is that one of Python's best vectors for growth is not converting &lt;em&gt;current&lt;/em&gt; programmers from other languages to Python (a 'Red Ocean' strategy), but converting current non-programmers &lt;em&gt;into&lt;/em&gt; programmers by demonstrating Python's utility (a 'Blue Ocean' strategy). In this case, the spreadsheet user (who's already one of the closest things to a programmer in most organizations) is our audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This session focuses on working with data that's in spreadsheets by 'talking' directly to the spreadsheets with Python. There are two main focuses to the session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help grow the Python community by showing spreadsheet users how Python can help them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;speed up or eliminate repetitive tasks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;provide better and data analysis than a spreadsheet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expose Python developers to methods they can use to directly interact with spreadsheets, avoiding the 'delimited text file' intermediary step&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kojo Idrissa</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-08-16:pytexas-2013/growing-python-with-spreadsheets.html</guid></item><item><title>Privilege Arbitrage</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pydx-2016/privilege-arbitrage.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyDX 2016 talk by Kojo Idrissa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multiple recent talks have highlighted the importance of an Inclusive culture for tech communities (coding, hackerspaces, etc). The question that often remains: HOW do we make these cultures more inclusive? This talk introduces Privilege Arbitrage as a method to promote that cultural change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is for people of all skill levels, interested in helping their tech community culture become more inclusive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kojo Idrissa</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-12-30:pydx-2016/privilege-arbitrage.html</guid></item><item><title>A D&amp;D-based guide to Contribution and Inclusion in the Python Community</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2014/a-dd-based-guide-to-contribution-and-inclusion-i.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Python community needs many different types of contributions to
thrive. If you ever thought, &amp;quot;I'm not a great programmer, so I can't
contribute to the Python community. :-(&amp;quot;, you're WRONG!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, using classes and roles from Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons (D&amp;amp;D) as a lens,
we'll look at multiple contributing roles in the Python community, and
how you can find one that fits you. Not familiar with D&amp;amp;D? I'll provide
a brief, relevant primer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, we'll continue the discussion to see how Inclusiveness helps us
get those different contributors into the Python community. To use D&amp;amp;D
language, a party of only one class won't go far. We'll also look at how
Inclusiveness is NOT the same thing as Diversity or Political
Correctness.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kojo Idrissa</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-05:pytexas-2014/a-dd-based-guide-to-contribution-and-inclusion-i.html</guid></item><item><title>Python and Spreadsheets: State of the Union, Oct 2014</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2014/python-and-spreadsheets-state-of-the-union-oct.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;At PyTexas 2013 I gave a talk on using Python to work with spreadsheets.
The landscape is rapidly changing and the options have expanded. This
talk will be a whirlwind tour of your options for using Python with
spreadsheets (NOT just Excel) as of late 2014. From processing
spreadsheet &lt;em&gt;files&lt;/em&gt; to using Python to directly control a spreadsheet
app, we'll see what's available, with a focus on how it can help &lt;strong&gt;you&lt;/strong&gt;
with what you work on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kojo Idrissa</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-04:pytexas-2014/python-and-spreadsheets-state-of-the-union-oct.html</guid></item><item><title>Building a More Inclusive Python Community Culture</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2015/building-a-more-inclusive-python-community-cultur.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Groups that are more diverse are &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.google.com/#q=diverse+%22problem+solving%22"&gt;better at solving
problems&lt;/a&gt;
than more homogenous groups. An inclusive group culture maximizes the
odds of attracting and retaining skills &amp;amp; personalities needed to
thrive. The Python community has a pretty good track record on issues
related to inclusion. So, how can you help continue that trend,
especially in your local community? I'll start with a brief &lt;em&gt;WHY&lt;/em&gt; and
&lt;em&gt;WHAT&lt;/em&gt; of Inclusion, but most of this talk focuses on &lt;strong&gt;HOW&lt;/strong&gt; to help
your local corner of the Python community be as Inclusive as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kojo Idrissa</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-09:pytexas-2015/building-a-more-inclusive-python-community-cultur.html</guid><category>inclusion</category><category>diversity</category><category>Community</category><category>Culture</category></item><item><title>How to Practice Inclusion and Benefit Django</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-2015/how-to-practice-inclusion-and-benefit-django-by.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How to Practice Inclusion and Benefit Django by Kojo Idrissa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WHAT: Inclusion Defined&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not about morality Inclusion vs. Diversity vs. Political Correctness
WHY: Why does this matter?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inherent limits on community membership: not ALL 7 billion humans will
join AND contribute Inclusion lets you maximize the number of
contributors HOW: How do I DO this better?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check your assumptions Zen of Python on Inclusiveness Errors should
never pass silently Check for exceptions Discuss errors when they occur
In the face of ambiguity, refuse the temptation to guess: how much does
the ambiguity matter? Get out of your bubble Flip the Demographics
Understanding The Power of Privilege Your Personal Privilege Matrix
Privilege Arbitrage &amp;quot;Turn Your Sadness Into Kindness&amp;quot; Closing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if you feel you can't?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your heart's not really into it or you feel it's &amp;quot;too hard&amp;quot;, be
honest with yourself and just hang around others like you. An insincere
effort often does more harm than good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recognize that this behavior may leave you isolated from a large (and
growing) portion of the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's up to all of us&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as systems tend towards entropy, if you leave a community alone it
tends towards toxicity. Good communities require continual effort. -
Jacob Kaplan-Moss&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Help us caption &amp;amp; translate this video!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://amara.org/v/HHB0/"&gt;http://amara.org/v/HHB0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kojo Idrissa</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-09-19:djangocon-2015/how-to-practice-inclusion-and-benefit-django-by.html</guid></item></channel></rss>