<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Building a cutting-edge data processing environment on a budget</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-russia-2015/building-a-cutting-edge-data-processing-environment-on-a-budget.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a penniless academic I wanted to do &amp;quot;big data&amp;quot; for science. Open
source, Python, and simple patterns were the way forward. Staying on top
of todays growing datasets is an arm race. Data analytics machinery
—clusters, NOSQL, visualization, Hadoop, machine learning, ...— can
spread a team's resources thin. Focusing on simple patterns, lightweight
technologies, and a good understanding of the applications gets us most
of the way for a fraction of the cost. These patterns appear underline
the design of Mayavi, for interactive 3D visualization, scikit-learn, for
easy machine learning, and joblib for out-of-core and parallel computing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will present a personal perspective on ten years of scientific data
processing with Python. What are the emerging patterns in data
processing? How can modern data-mining ideas be used without a big
engineering team? What constraints and design trade-offs govern software
projects like scikit-learn, Mayavi, or joblib? How can we make the most
out of distributed hardware with simple framework-less code?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Gael Varoquaux</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-09-18:pycon-russia-2015/building-a-cutting-edge-data-processing-environment-on-a-budget.html</guid></item><item><title>Statistics in Python</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2015/statistics-in-python.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This tutorial will focus on inferential and exploratory statistics in Python: modelling statistical relationship between variables. It will give an introduction to pandas for consistent manipulation of heterogeneous set of variables (for example gender and age) and to statsmodel to estimate a test statistical models.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Gaël Varoquaux</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-05:euroscipy-2015/statistics-in-python.html</guid></item><item><title>Scientist meets web dev: how Python became the language of data</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/europython-2016/scientist-meets-web-dev-how-python-became-the-language-of-data.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gaël Varoquaux - Scientist meets web dev: how Python became the language of data
[EuroPython 2016]
[22 July 2016]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/keynote-science-web-dev"&gt;https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/keynote-science-web-dev&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data science is a hot topic and  Python has emerged as an ideal language for it.
Its strength for data analysis come from the cultural mix between the scientific Python community, and more conventional software usage, such as web development or system administration. I'll show how and why Python is a easy and powerful tool for data science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python started as a scripting language, but now it is the new trend everywhere and in particular for data science, the latest rage of computing. It didn't get there by chance: tools and concepts built by nerdy scientists and geek sysadmins provide foundations for what is said to be the sexiest job: data scientist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my talk I'll give a personal perspective, historical and technical, on the progress of the scientific Python ecosystem, from numerical physics to data mining. What made Python suitable for science; How could scipy grow to challenge commercial giants such as Matlab; Why the cultural gap between scientific Python and the broader Python community turned out to be a gold mine; How scikit-learn was born, what technical decisions enabled it to grow; And last but not least, how we are addressing a wider and wider public, lowering the bar and empowering people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will discuss low-level technical aspects, such as how the Python world makes it easy to move large chunks of number across code. It will touch upon current exciting developments in scikit-learn and joblib. But it will also talk about softer topics, such as project dynamics or documentation, as software's success is determined by people.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Gaël Varoquaux</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-07:europython-2016/scientist-meets-web-dev-how-python-became-the-language-of-data.html</guid></item><item><title>Opening Keynote - Gaël Varoquaux, Inria</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pydata-paris-2015/opening-keynote-gael-varoquaux-inria.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gaël Varoquaux is an INRIA faculty researcher working on computational
science for brain imaging in the Neurospin brain research institute
(Paris, France). His research focuses on modeling and mining brain
activity in relation to cognition. Years before the NSA, he was hoping
to make bleeding-edge data processing available across new fields, and
he has been working on a mastermind plan building easy-to-use
open-source software in Python. He is a core developer of scikit-learn,
joblib, and Mayavi, a nominated member of the PSF, and often teaches
scientific computing with Python using
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://scipy-lectures.github.com/"&gt;http://scipy-lectures.github.com/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Gaël Varoquaux</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-04-09:pydata-paris-2015/opening-keynote-gael-varoquaux-inria.html</guid></item></channel></rss>