<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_lauris-jullien.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Asynchronous network requests in a web application</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/europython-2016/asynchronous-network-requests-in-a-web-application.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Lauris Jullien</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-04:europython-2016/asynchronous-network-requests-in-a-web-application.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lauris Jullien - Asynchronous network requests in a web application
[EuroPython 2016]
[21 July 2016]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/asynchronous-network-requests-in-a-web-application"&gt;https://ep2016.europython.eu//conference/talks/asynchronous-network-requests-in-a-web-application&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introducing  asynchronous calls from within an endpoint in a web app
can be desirable but hard to achieve.
This talk will explore different solutions for this (running Twisted
event loop, Co-Routines, Asyncio, …) and how well they play with the
different parallelization models of common WSGI web servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the more and more popular SOA paradigm, it’s common for services to
have to compose responses with resources from many different services.
Everyone’s first idea will probably be to call each service
synchronously with your favorite python HTTP library. This
unfortunately doesn’t scale well and tens of successive network calls
will make your endpoints painfully slow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One solution is to parallelize these network calls. If you are already
using an asynchronous web app (such as Tornado or Twisted), more
asynchronous in your asynchronous shouldn’t be much of a challenge.
But if you chose not to dive into the madness of chained Deferred
calls, and used a standard prefork/threaded WSGI web server (such as
Gunicorn or uWSGI) to run your Django/Flask/Pyramid application, you
might find yourself wondering how to manage these asynchronous calls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will explore different solutions (running Twisted event
loop, Co-Routines, Asyncio, …) and how well they play with the
different parallelization models of WSGI web servers.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>