<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Object oriented Programming with NumPy using CPython &amp; PyPy</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/object-oriented-programming-with-numpy-using-cpyt.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the paper we compare object-oriented implementations of an advection
algorithm written in Python, C++ and modern FORTRAN. The main angles of
comparison are code brevity and syntax clarity (and hence
maintainability and auditability) as well as performance. A notable
performance gain when switching from CPython to PyPy will be
exemplified, and the reasons for it will be briefly explained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the paper we compare object-oriented implementations of an advection
algorithm written in Python, C++ and modern FORTRAN. The MPDATA
advection algorithm (Multidimensional Positive-Definite Advective
Transport Algorithm) used as a core of weather, ocean and climate
modelling systems serves as an example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the context of scientific programming, employment of object-oriented
programming (OOP) techniques may help to improve code readability, and
hence its auditability and maintainability. OOP offers, in particular,
the possibility to reproduce in the program code the mathematical
&amp;quot;blackboard abstractions&amp;quot; used in the literature. We compare how the
choice of a particular language influences syntax clarity, code length
and the performance: CPU time and memory usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Python implementation of MPDATA is based on NumPy. Its performance
is compared with C++/Blitz++ and FORTRAN implementations. A notable
performance gain when switching from the standard CPython to PyPy will
be exemplified, and the reasons for it will be briefly explained.
Discussion of other selected solutions for improving the NumPy’s
relatively poor performance will be also presented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will describe and extend on the key findings presented in
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1301.1334"&gt;http://arxiv.org/abs/1301.1334&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dorota Jarecka</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-09:scipy-2014/object-oriented-programming-with-numpy-using-cpyt.html</guid><category>pypy</category></item></channel></rss>