<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_ian-huston.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>How Data Science fits in the Balanced Team</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-ireland-2016/how-data-science-fits-in-the-balanced-team.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ian Huston</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-11-06:pycon-ireland-2016/how-data-science-fits-in-the-balanced-team.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The goal of a Balanced Team is to share ownership and responsibility
for the success of a project between team members. Each team member
has specific obligations to the team and a specific area of authority.
Until recently, designers, product managers and developers were the
usual team members considered. In this talk I will explore how data
scientists can function in a balanced team and discuss my experience
working as a data scientist on balanced teams at Pivotal Labs with our
global clients. I will consider what obligations and authority a data
scientist can provide as part of a balanced team and how this
situation differs from the usual jack-of-all-trades type data science
work. I will outline specific examples where data science can help
user centric design and product management, and where the practices of
lean-startup and agile development can help accelerate analysis and
data science. Based on my experience building data science driven
products with a global bank and European car manufacturers, I will
outline what we tried, what worked and most importantly what didn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a data scientist or need to work with one, this talk will
equip you to understand how data science can be an integral part of a
balanced team.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>