<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_sarah-bird.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Let it shine - telling your data story</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pydata-carolinas-2016/let-it-shine-telling-your-data-story.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sarah Bird</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-15:pydata-carolinas-2016/let-it-shine-telling-your-data-story.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You work for weeks on a new analysis, collecting, cleaning data,
modeling it, you arrive at a new result. What happens next? How many
people explore your results--and wider work? Bokeh is a data
visualization library that gives you the power of web-based custom
interactive visualizations, but lets you build them in Python. We'll
talk about moving seamlessly from analysis to engaging presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You work for weeks, maybe months, on a new analysis: collecting data,
cleaning it, extracting your features and modeling it, and you finally
come up with some meaningful results... What happens next? How many
people dig into and explore your work and your results?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bokeh is a data visualization library that gives you the power of
custom interactive visualizations that you can publish on the web, but
lets you build them in python.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Getting Started with Bokeh</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pydata-carolinas-2016/getting-started-with-bokeh.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sarah Bird</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-14:pydata-carolinas-2016/getting-started-with-bokeh.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bokeh is a python interactive visualization library that uses web
browsers for its presentation. Bokeh supports a wide variety of
visualization tasks from basic exploration through to building
advanced data applications. In this tutorial we'll cover Bokeh's basic
concepts and go from plotting a scatter plot to building an
interactive dashboard that can run a clustering algorithm from a
dropdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bokeh is a python interactive visualization library that uses web
browsers for its presentation. Bokeh supports a wide variety of
visualization tasks from basic exploration through to building
advanced data applications. In this tutorial we'll cover Bokeh's basic
concepts and go from plotting a scatter plot to building an
interactive dashboard that can run a clustering algorithm from a
dropdown - you'll be surprised how easy that is.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Getting started with Bokeh / Let's build an interactive data visualization for the web..in Python!</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/europython-2015/getting-started-with-bokeh-lets-build-an-interactive-data-visualization-for-the-webin-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sarah Bird</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-06:europython-2015/getting-started-with-bokeh-lets-build-an-interactive-data-visualization-for-the-webin-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sarah Bird - Getting started with Bokeh / Let's build an interactive data visualization for the web..in Python!
[EuroPython 2015]
[20 July 2015]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: [birdsarah.github.io/europython-2015-bokeh][1]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a web developer, I find myself being asked to make increasing
numbers of data visualizations, interactive infographics, and more.
d3.js is great, as are many other javascript toolkits that are out
there. But if I can write more Python and less JavaScript... well,
that makes me happy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bokeh is a new Python library for interactive visualization. Its
origins are in the data science community, but it has a lot to offer
web developers. In this mini-tutorial, I'll run through how to build a
data visualization in Bokeh and how to hook it into your web
application. This will be a real-world example, that was previously
built in d3.js.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along the way, I'll provide tips and tricks that I've discovered in my
experience including how Bokeh works wonderfully with the iPython
notebook which I use to prototype my visualizations, and many data
science people use as their native way to explore data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those of you who already know a little Bokeh, I'll be covering the
new &amp;quot;actions framework&amp;quot; that lets you write JS callbacks in your
python code so you can do lots of interactions all on the client side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://birdsarah.github.io/europython-2015-bokeh/"&gt;http://birdsarah.github.io/europython-2015-bokeh/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Interactive data for the web</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2015/interactive-data-for-the-web.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Sarah Bird</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-04-12:pycon-us-2015/interactive-data-for-the-web.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Interactive data visualization libraries are mostly a JavaScript
stronghold. The new Python library, Bokeh, provides a simple, clean way
to make more shiny things. Although it comes from the data science
community, it has a lot to offer web developers. For a visualization you
might have built in d3.js, I'll show how to build it in Bokeh, how to
test it, and how to hook it into your web app.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>