<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>O que é esse tal de REST?</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/python-brasil-2016/o-que-e-esse-tal-de-rest.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;REST é a bola vez quando falamos sobre API. As maioria dos serviços que
encontramos na web fornece interfaces deste tipo para que possamos
desenvolver integrações. Será mesmo que estas APIs podem ser
consideradas RESTful? O que é preciso para que uma API seja considerada
RESTful? Você sabia que este padrão já existe a mais de 15 anos? Nesta
palestra vamos nos aprofundar no tema e entender os conceitos e
&lt;em&gt;constraints&lt;/em&gt; de um sistema RESTful para que possamos explorar suas
vantagens na hora de arquitetar nossa próxima API web.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Filipe Ximenes</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-15:python-brasil-2016/o-que-e-esse-tal-de-rest.html</guid></item><item><title>What is wrong with API wrappers and how can we do better</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/europython-2015/what-is-wrong-with-api-wrappers-and-how-can-we-do-better.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Filipe Ximenes - What is wrong with API wrappers and how can we do better
[EuroPython 2015]
[20 July 2015]
[Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wrappers are an essential tool for interacting with web APIs. They
reduce the amount of work needed to make requests and sometimes, only
sometimes prevent the developer from dealing with extensive
documentations. It’s common to encounter libs that require not only
the study of their own documentation, but also the APIs one,
duplicating the needed work. This is caused because wrappers do not
follow a design pattern, each developer creates it’s own design,
coding style and use their preferred tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Tapioca][1] is what can be called: &amp;quot;a wrapper generator”. Creating API wrappers with Tapioca is extremely easy and fast. For example, it took 1 hour to write the full wrapper for the [Parse.com][2] REST API. But this is not the more important thing, Tapioca libs have a similar interface so once understood how they work, developers can work with any other without the need to learn a new interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tapioca is also thought to comply with REST features and takes HATEOAS
(Hypermedia as the engine of application state) seriously, so
“following” links and pagination are natively supported. Explorability
is also a key concept and developers are encouraged to play with
Tapioca packages and find their way through APIs before writing their
final code. Although there are some production ready [Tapioca
wrappers][3], it is a work in progress, there are still many features
to be explored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/vintasoftware/tapioca-wrapper"&gt;https://github.com/vintasoftware/tapioca-wrapper&lt;/a&gt;
[2]: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://parse.com"&gt;http://parse.com&lt;/a&gt;
[3]: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/vintasoftware/tapioca-wrapper#tapioca-comes-in-many-flavours"&gt;https://github.com/vintasoftware/tapioca-wrapper#tapioca-comes-in-many-flavours&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Filipe Ximenes</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-02:europython-2015/what-is-wrong-with-api-wrappers-and-how-can-we-do-better.html</guid></item></channel></rss>