<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Deploying test and production systems with Ansible</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/kiwi-pycon-2014/deploying-test-and-production-systems-with-ansibl.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Audience level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intermediate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk presents Ansible as a light-weight, simple and effective
configuration management tool. We will see why configuration management
is important and how we can use Ansible to automatically deploy and test
full production clusters - showcased with a sample Django application -
with just a single command and in a number of different environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With modern configuration, deployment and orchestration systems,
software developers can easily maintain, bring up and tear down local
test systems, staging, demonstration and production systems, which are
100% identical to each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation will give an introduction to Ansible, a modern, simple
and efficient configuration management system. We will see how we can
deploy complete clusters (with load balancers, database and some Django
application servers), reliably and fully automated, either on dedicated
servers, on local virtual machines or in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If all goes well, there will even be a live demo in which we will bring
up a complete cluster or two in different environments, to illustrate
the power of this approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/nzpug/juergen-brendel-deploying-test-and-production-systems-with-ansible"&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/nzpug/juergen-brendel-deploying-test-and-production-systems-with-ansible&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Juergen Brendel</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-09-14:kiwi-pycon-2014/deploying-test-and-production-systems-with-ansibl.html</guid><category>talk</category></item><item><title>PyConAU 2010: Introducing Python to a Java shop</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2010/pyconau-2010--introducing-python-to-a-java-shop.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Introducing Python to a Java shop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Juergen Brendel (MuleSoft)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a time and place for everything: For some applications Python
is perfect, for others a language like Java and its entire ecosystem is
more ideal. In this talk we see how Python was introduced to a Java shop
as a vehicle for rapid and dynamic prototyping of a new project. The
talk then explains how Jython/Java integration was used to translate
this project step by step from Python to Java. Going beyond the advocacy
focus, the talk then shows the interfaces to call Java from Python and
vice versa and illustrates those with examples. Furthermore, unit
testing of Java classes via test cases written in Python is also touched
upon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Juergen Brendel</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 1990 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,1990-01-01:pycon-au-2010/pyconau-2010--introducing-python-to-a-java-shop.html</guid><category>advocacy</category><category>jython</category><category>prototyping</category><category>pyconau</category><category>pyconau2010</category></item></channel></rss>