<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bridging the gap: from Data Science to service</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pydata-berlin-2016/bridging-the-gap-from-data-science-to-service.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Berlin 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent years have brought an explosion of algorithms, models and software libraries for doing data science that allow unprecedented possibilities for solving problems. But providing a data science service as a consultant or a company involves more than just tools. In this talk, I will share the most useful lessons that I learned while working at a company providing these services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Providing consulting services or custom machine learning based tools involves many elements beyond choosing the right models, analysis methods and tools. While working at Machinalis, we learned a set of ideas that help us to make our projects successful, which have more to do with the human and engineering side of the service than the science and programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of the talk is to share that experience with people that are providing or planning to provide services based on data science. It presents some tips and explains how they work and the kind of problems that they avoid. The content of the talk is divided into two main areas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tips related to team collaboration. These include aspects to consider regarding how and what to communicate between different roles in the team (data scientists, developers, project managers, people doing labeling or entry, etc.), and how to make certain decisions that the team faces (choosing tools, knowing when to do a flimsy proof of concept vs when to create robust products using best practices, etc.).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tips related to collaboration with clients and users. There are different kinds of clients with varied levels of knowledge regarding the possibilities and limits of data science, and each kind requires an appropriate way of communicating these issues. It is also important to establish clarity about mutual expectations, about what is guaranteed and what is experimental, about how your work will be evaluated, and about how you will integrate with different stakeholders in the client's organization. This alignment with your client is a critical element of a successful service.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/machinalis/slides/tree/master/data-science-to-service"&gt;https://github.com/machinalis/slides/tree/master/data-science-to-service&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Daniel Moisset</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-05-31:pydata-berlin-2016/bridging-the-gap-from-data-science-to-service.html</guid></item><item><title>Finding relations in documents with IEPY</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2016/finding-relations-in-documents-with-iepy.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Amsterdam 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IEPY is an open source tool to identify relations between entities described in natural language documents. This talk will show you what can you use it for, what it can and can not do, and describe some real world examples of its use. You should come if you're dealing with information extraction problems on text, and after the talk you'll know if IEPY is the tool for you and what you need to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IEPY is an open source tool to identify entities and relations between them, as described in natural language documents. In other words, it is a tool for extracting structured information from unstructured sources. It was developed as a joint project between Machinalis and the Natural Language Processing research group of the University at Cordoba, Argentina. It recently won the 2015 Sadosky Award for &amp;quot;Industry and Academy Collaboration Project&amp;quot;. IEPY is developed in python and can apply and mix rule based approaches, machine learning approaches, and manual tagging. It is actually designed to allow a hybrid approach (starting for rules, machine learning from that, using a human to clarify uncertain cases, and then integrate human answers in the machine learning model, etc). It includes the document store, learning engine, and a user interface to make it practical to provide manually tagged inputs by non-technical people. This talk will give an overview of what IEPY does (and general details on how it does it), but will be strongly focused on what kind of problems it is best applied to, what are the main situations where it can be challenging to implement it. I will support that description showcasing two of our main success cases: one analysis that was done over the techcrunch news articles to detect funding events, and one analysis done over military files from the last dictatorship in Argentina to help track people involved in human rights violations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Daniel Moisset</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-03-26:pydata-amsterdam-2016/finding-relations-in-documents-with-iepy.html</guid><category>iepy</category></item></channel></rss>