<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>JSON Standards for the Web</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2015/json-standards-for-the-web.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;RESTful APIs reign supreme! No longer do developers have to put up with
SOAP and XML-RPC and those bulky, schema laden exchanges. JSON maps
almost directly to python and we're flying again!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over time the chaos of free form JSON representations has subsided and a
number of best practices have appeared such that we now expect certain
patterns when encountering a new JSON REST API. The next step is to
standardize these practices and start offering the predictability and
code reuse we lost years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will provide an overview of current attempts at standardizing
JSON exchanges such as jsonapi, jsonhome and jsonschema.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jamie Lennox</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-04:pycon-au-2015/json-standards-for-the-web.html</guid></item><item><title>Practical Federated Identity</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2015/practical-federated-identity.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Federated Identity was once again a highlight of the OpenStack summit in
Vancouver this time with the announcement of keystone to keystone
federation that will pave the way for inter-cloud workloads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past I have done presentations on what Federated Identity is,
however in this talk we delve into the more practical requirements of
connecting to an IdP, discuss the changes in workflow required to
authenticate your applications, how to configure web single sign on with
horizon, what is possible today and the pain points you may encounter
using federation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jamie Lennox</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2015-08-04:pycon-au-2015/practical-federated-identity.html</guid></item></channel></rss>