<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pyvideo.org/feeds/speaker_erik-tollerud.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2015-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Astropy in 2015</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/scipy-2015/astropy-in-2015.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Erik Tollerud</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-07-10:scipy-2015/astropy-in-2015.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Astropy - Herding Snakes or Astronomers: which is more difficult?</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/scipy-2012/astropy-herding-snakes-or-astronomers-which-is.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Erik Tollerud</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2012-07-18:scipy-2012/astropy-herding-snakes-or-astronomers-which-is.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Developers and users of astronomical software have long bemoaned the
absence of shared efforts in the field. While there are well known, free
software tools available for astronomy, most have been developed by
large institutions, and the past few decades have seen comparatively
little progress in fostering a community-based set of software tools.
There is hope that is changing now. The continuing growth of Python in
astronomy has led to an increasing awareness of needless duplication of
efforts within the community and the need to make existing packages work
better with each other; such discussions came to a head on the astropy
email list in the spring of 2011 leading to formation of the astropy
project. The first coordination meeting was held in the fall of 2011,
and significant progress has been made in setting up a community
repository of core astronomical packages. We will describe the general
goals of astropy and the progress that has been made to date.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Astronomy Mini-Symposia"></category></entry><entry><title>Astropy, growing a community-based software system for astronomy</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/scipy-2013/astropy-growing-a-community-based-software-syste-0.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Erik Tollerud</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2013-07-01:scipy-2013/astropy-growing-a-community-based-software-syste-0.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Astropy is a community-based software project to coordinate the
development of libraries and applications for astronomy. We will report
on progress that has been made with astropy since the last scipy
conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Authors: Droettboom, Michael, STScI; Robitaille, Thomas, Max Planck
Institute; Tollerud, Erik, Yale Universit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Track: Astronomy and Astrophysics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Astropy is a community-based software project to coordinate the
development of libraries and applications for astronomy. We will report
on progress that has been made with astropy since the last scipy
conference. The past year has seen much growth in the number and quality
of the core libraries in astropy and a public release. We will highlight
the new capabilities available, and outline the development plans for
the upcoming year. Finally we discuss the strategies for advertising its
capabilities and growing the documentation and tutorials available for
users and developers.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="astronomy"></category><category term="astrophysics"></category><category term="astropy"></category></entry></feed>