<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>AutoDocish: Automated-ish Dataset Documentation</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pydata-chicago-2016/autodocish-automated-ish-dataset-documentation.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Chicago 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://figshare.com/articles/AutoDocish_Automated-ish_Dataset_Documentation/3759288/1"&gt;https://figshare.com/articles/AutoDocish_Automated-ish_Dataset_Documentation/3759288/1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AutoDocish is a command line Python tool to semi-automate the dataset documentation process. Written with a framework for expansion and customization, it produces template files in MarkDown that contain a basic data dictionary structure. This talk explains dataset documentation practices and how this tool could fit into the data publishing workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Elizabeth Wickes</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-28:pydata-chicago-2016/autodocish-automated-ish-dataset-documentation.html</guid><category>documentation</category></item><item><title>Integrating Development, Documentation and Reporting</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-2013/integrating-development-documentation-and-reporting.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s explore the amazing things that happen when you combine reporting with documentation. We’ll start with a retro-chic command-line task management tool named ‘ado’, and create a beautifully modern D3-based interactive task explorer (no server necessary). Learn how powerful documentation-driven development can be, and the benefits of freeing documentation and reporting from their usual separate silos. In this talk we will simultaneously document Bash, Python, SQL, CSS, HTML and JavaScript using HTML, PDF, epub, Excel and .docx formats (with just a single command!). You’ll learn about Dexy, the document and data automation tool that makes this possible by working alongside the documentation tools you already know and love.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ana Nelson</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-04-09:write-the-docs-2013/integrating-development-documentation-and-reporting.html</guid><category>documentation</category><category>tools</category></item><item><title>Why Projects Should Have “What’s New” Documents</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-2013/why-projects-should-have-whats-new-documents.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Describes the speaker's experience writing What’s New documents covering the new features in each Python 2.x release. The editorial policies will be summarized, and the speaker argues that large projects should include a “What’s New” as part of their standard documentation set.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Andrew Kuchling</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2013-04-08:write-the-docs-2013/why-projects-should-have-whats-new-documents.html</guid><category>documentation</category></item><item><title>Documentation at Scale</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-2014/documentation-at-scale.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Information is powerful — every day we see it transform the world around us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documentation doesn't always have to be about a software workflow or open source project — it can be used to develop and convey ideas much larger than yourself. Information architecture is a powerful tool for developing ideas over time. It enables us to evolve and distill information at a much larger scale than a single person or team could ever achieve on their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take these concepts, and apply open source workflow tools like GitHub's Pull Requests and Write the Docs, and the distributed evolution of ideas and information has never been more accessible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll explore these concepts, learn how to foster a community of distributed contributors, encourage contributions early on, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python-Guide.org will be used as an example, a Python-specific knowledge base written by 168 people and accessed by over 50,000 people every month.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kenneth Reitz</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-05-05:write-the-docs-2014/documentation-at-scale.html</guid><category>documentation</category></item><item><title>Documenting Domain Specific Knowledge</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/write-the-docs-2014/documenting-domain-specific-knowledge.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most of my career as a software engineer, I've written documentation for very general purpose tools, where users' had an existing familiarity. For the last six months I've been working on a cryptography library, a domain most developers are ignorant of. We set out with the goal of making our documentation accessible to any developer, regardless of previous cryptographic experience, which presents unique challenges. This talk will dive into what these challenges are, and how we try to solve them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alex Gaynor</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-05-05:write-the-docs-2014/documenting-domain-specific-knowledge.html</guid><category>documentation</category></item><item><title>Read the docs</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycaribbean-2016/eric-holscher-read-the-docs.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Eric Holscher</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-02-21:pycaribbean-2016/eric-holscher-read-the-docs.html</guid><category>keynote</category><category>read the docs</category><category>documentation</category><category>sphinx</category></item><item><title>Large Problems in Django, Mostly Solved</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-2010/djangocon-2010--large-problems-in-django--mostly-.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk is based on my popular series of blog posts highlighting
applications from the community. I will highlight some of the best
applications that the Django/Python community has put together, talk
about places that are lacking, and talk about what these popular
applications have in common.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part 1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have written a series of blog posts about &amp;quot;Large problems&amp;quot; in the
community, and how they have been solved by members of our community
with reusable apps. Previously I have covered:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delayed Execution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;APIs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Database Migrations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will update my thoughts on these issues, as well as talking about a
couple of other new issues that I think that have been solved in a
decent way. These include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remote Command Execution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debugging in Development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continuous Integration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part 2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this part I will highlight issues that are still headaches for the
Community. These are places where there is a good chance for growth for
third party apps, and places where I have personally found some friction
in my development. A couple examples of this are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deployment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Class Based Views / Thread Safety&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debugging Production Environments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part 3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the above applications that are well done, what makes a popular
reusable app? This won't be my thoughts, but more looking at apps that
have been successful and trying to see what they have in common. A good
app and a good reusable app are necessarily different, and I think it
will be interesting to look at what traits make reusable apps popular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ericholscher.com/tag/largeproblems/"&gt;Large problems posts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Eric Holscher</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2010-09-08:djangocon-2010/djangocon-2010--large-problems-in-django--mostly-.html</guid><category>api</category><category>ci</category><category>continuousintegration</category><category>databasemigrations</category><category>debugging</category><category>delayedexecutions</category><category>deployment</category><category>djangocon</category><category>djangocon2010</category><category>documentation</category><category>migrations</category><category>safety</category><category>search</category></item><item><title>The story and tech of Read the Docs</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-2011/djangocon-2011--the-story-and-tech-of-read-the-do.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The story and tech of Read the Docs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Eric Holscher&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hosting open source documentation was a mess. The best-of-class solution
for the Python world as uploading a tarball of html to
packages.python.org or doing similar to upload to github pages. We set
out to solve this problem using the current best of class tools that
Django has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Eric Holscher</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 1990 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,1990-01-01:djangocon-2011/djangocon-2011--the-story-and-tech-of-read-the-do.html</guid><category>casestudy</category><category>djangocon</category><category>djangocon2011</category><category>documentation</category><category>readthedocs</category><category>rtd</category><category>rtfd</category></item><item><title>Using Python in Software for the Medical Industry</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/using-python-in-software-for-the-medical-industry.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] wesley chun - 21 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Tagliatelle&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The medical industry has long been dominated by custom software written
by manufacturers of medical equipment. With the widespread use of
lower-cost computing power and abundance of software developers using
cost-beneficial open source development tools, it is no surprise that
this is a rapidly- growing field in software engineering. In this talk,
I will describe some of my experiences using Python and other open
source tools, temporarily transitioning from the world of the web and
Internet development, jumping into the medical industry, an experience
much like being a fish out of water. The experiences of working in this
field, specifically developing software for use in clinical trials. We
describe the use of open source tools for such software development, the
required integration with closed-source software, and the documentation
rigor that is necessary in a field under the jurisdiction of the US Food
and Drug Administration (FDA). In particular, I'll describe direct
experience in building an application for the use of analyzing spinal
fractures and the various tools that make up the application suite,
whose primary development language was Python. We will also discuss the
particular role of the my employer at the time in the clinical trials
process and elaborate on the data flow that was necessary for all
medical applications developed at the firm, not just the one in
particular.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wesley J. Chun</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-18:europython-2011/using-python-in-software-for-the-medical-industry.html</guid><category>documentation</category><category>web</category></item><item><title>Writing Books using Python and Open Source Software (#40)</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2010/writing-books-using-python-and-open-source-softwa.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Writing Books using Python and Open Source Software&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Mr. wesley j. chun&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days, there are countless number of software applications and web
services that have been developed using free and open source software
(FOSS). Such tools have become so flexible, powerful, and universal,
that it should also be possible for authors to write manuscripts using
open source tools like Python in the same way that applications are
developed. In this talk, we present some case studies of this
phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wesley J. Chun</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2010-02-19:pycon-us-2010/writing-books-using-python-and-open-source-softwa.html</guid><category>documentation</category><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2010</category><category>tools</category></item><item><title>Documentation Driven Development</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--documentation-driven-development.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Documentation Driven Development&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Corey Oordt&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers usually leave documentation as a final step; one that they
will get to as soon as they are forced with threats of bodily harm.
Writing the documentation before writing the code, can lead to better
code, better implementation and, of course, actual documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Documentation Driven Design&amp;quot; was coined by our team after noticing how
documenting code dramatically changed how we approached problems. By
writing the documentation first, you saw the problem from a different
perspective: the end user or programmer. This talk will focus on a few
items:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usable, not just functional. Many times developers write code that
solves the problem, but is a real pain in the neck to use. Writing the
documentation first demonstrates how easy or difficult it is to
implement the solution right away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A guide to what to write. Many developers leave documentation undone
because they don't know how to approach it. Having some idea of what
needs writing can make the task seem less daunting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Corey Oordt</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--documentation-driven-development.html</guid><category>documentation</category><category>documentationdrivendesign</category><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2011</category></item><item><title>Writing great documentation</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--writing-great-documentation.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Writing great documentation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Jacob Kaplan-Moss&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Django’s among the best documented open source projects; I'm intensely
proud of that accomplishment. If any part of Django endures, I hope
it’ll be a “documentation culture” — an ethos that values great,
well-written documentation. To that end, this talk looks at the tools,
tips, and techniques I’ve learned over the years. I hope it helps you
write great documentation, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk looks at tips, tools, and techniques you can use to produce
great technical documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's split roughly into two parts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Part 1: technique. We'll look at the structural elements that make
documentation useful: tutorials, high-level overviews, topical
guides, reference material, FAQs, and more. We'll cover some tips on
how to get documentation done, and community processes for handling
documentation in teams (open or not). We'll also talk about what I'm
calling &amp;quot;Documentation Driven Development&amp;quot; - a technique riffing off
Test Driven Development that calls for writing documentation before
code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Part 2: tools. Over the last couple of years a few fantastic tools
have sprung up that ease the technical aspects of writing
documentation. We'll talk about which tools are suitable for which
uses, and look at a handful of cool tools including
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://sphinx.pocoo.org/"&gt;Sphinx&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://epydoc.sourceforge.net/"&gt;Epydoc&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://fitzgen.github.com/pycco/"&gt;http://fitzgen.github.com/pycco/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is mostly targeted towards those documenting libraries or
frameworks intended for use by other developers, but much of it probably
applies to any sort of technical documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jacob Kaplan-Moss</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--writing-great-documentation.html</guid><category>docs</category><category>documentation</category><category>epydoc</category><category>faqs</category><category>pycco</category><category>pycon</category><category>pycon2011</category><category>sphinx</category></item></channel></rss>