<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Micropython for Mews</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pydx-2016/micropython-for-mews.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyDX 2016 talk by Sev Leonard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never miss a photo from your favorite internet cat again. Learn how to make a small wifi-connected badge using micropython and some snazzy electronics. No experience required! This talk will chronicle the experience of a first time micropythonista setting up the ESP8266 wifi module with an LCD display using the Arduino IDE. Attendees will learn how to get setup to program microcontrollers with micropython, how to connect to wifi to get the latest cat pics, and how to display kittens on an LCD.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sev Leonard</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-12-30:pydx-2016/micropython-for-mews.html</guid><category>micropython</category><category>ESP8266</category></item><item><title>Micro Python - shrinking Python down to run on a microcontroller</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-uk-2014/micro-python-shrinking-python-down-to-run-on-a-microcontroller.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Presented by: Damien George&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Micro Python is a rewrite of the Python language that uses minimal RAM and which is optimised to run on a microcontroller (basically a very small computer). I will outline the architecture of Micro Python, explain how it minimises RAM usage, and discuss its benefits and use in the embedded electronics world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Damien George</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2014-10-14:pycon-uk-2014/micro-python-shrinking-python-down-to-run-on-a-microcontroller.html</guid><category>MicroPython</category></item><item><title>MicroPython: Embedded programming for everyone</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2016/micropython-embedded-programming-for-everyone.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jim Mussared
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/110/view_talk"&gt;https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/110/view_talk&lt;/a&gt;
Embedded programming allows students to take their programs into the physical world - to build robots and interactive gadgets with sensors and displays. Until recently, this has been almost exclusively the domain of lower level languages like C which is not known for its beginner friendliness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MicroPython is an optimized implementation of Python 3 designed to be run on the sort of embedded microcontrollers that are making their way into the classroom, allowing Python to take the place of C. In particular, the BBC MicroBit, the pyboard and the ESP8266 all now support MicroPython.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By using a language that students are already familiar with, more time can be spent on fun things like building robots and less time debugging code or setting up development tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the problems with teaching embedded programming in a classroom environment is the equipment required - both the actual boards and any additional accessories or modules. We will also demonstrate a browser-based MicroBit simulator which makes embedded programming accessible to more students and also allows for the creation of structured lessons, problems and assessments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jim Mussared</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-15:pycon-au-2016/micropython-embedded-programming-for-everyone.html</guid><category>MicroPython</category><category>education</category></item><item><title>MicroPython: a journey from Kickstarter to Space</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2016/micropython-a-journey-from-kickstarter-to-space.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Damien George
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/199/view_talk"&gt;https://2016.pycon-au.org/schedule/199/view_talk&lt;/a&gt;
MicroPython is a lean and efficient reimplementation of Python 3 with a
reduced standard library, and brings the awesomeness of Python to computing
devices with few resources, such as microcontrollers.  In this talk I will
detail my journey in building MicroPython and the various projects that it
has been used in and the people who are using it.  I will talk about running
a successful Kickstarter campaign (actually two of them!), circuit board
manufacturing, working with the European Space Agency, working with the BBC
on the micro:bit project, and the challenges of managing and funding
open-source software.  There will also be some live demos!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Damien George</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-13:pycon-au-2016/micropython-a-journey-from-kickstarter-to-space.html</guid><category>MicroPython</category></item><item><title>ESP8266 and MicroPython</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2016/esp8266-and-micropython.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ESP8266 is an exciting new WiFi enabled SoC which is not only small and fast but also very very cheap. And now it can run Python! This talk discusses the ins and outs of ESP8266 chips and modules, how to install MicroPython, and what you can do with it once you've installed it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nick Moore</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-12:pycon-au-2016/esp8266-and-micropython.html</guid><category>Internet-of-Things</category><category>MicroPython</category><category>ESP8266</category></item><item><title>Scripting the Internet of Things</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2016/scripting-the-internet-of-things.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A big part of the Internet of Things are the end nodes, such as sensors, that are controlled by microcontrollers or other small computing devices. These devices are getting more and more sophisticated and it can be beneficial to program them with a scripting language instead of a low-level language like C. Such scripting languages need to be implemented specifically to fit and run on a microcontroller and in this talk I will discuss a few of them: Python, Lua, JavaScript and Ruby. I will talk in detail about MicroPython, a lean and efficient reimplementation of Python 3 with a reduced standard library, that runs on microcontrollers and can be used to build Internet-of-Things devices. There will be plenty of time in the talk for questions and open discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Damien George</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-12:pycon-au-2016/scripting-the-internet-of-things.html</guid><category>Internet-of-Things</category><category>MicroPython</category></item><item><title>MicroPython: Python for microcontrollers and constrained environments</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-za-2016/micropython-python-for-microcontrollers-and-constrained-environments.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;MicroPython has risen from a kickstarter campaign to a feature rich
implementation of Python 3 on microcontrollers. The project is
summarized in the following statement: &amp;quot;MicroPython is a lean and
efficient implementation of the Python 3 programming language that
includes a small subset of the Python standard library and is optimised
to run on microcontrollers and in constrained environments&amp;quot;
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://micropython.org/"&gt;http://micropython.org/&lt;/a&gt;). With IOT gaining more momentum daily and
devices such as the ESP8266 (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.sparkfun.com/products/13678"&gt;https://www.sparkfun.com/products/13678&lt;/a&gt;)
now able to serve web pages, MicroPython is a viable candidate for fast
prototyping and simple embedded devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will focus mainly on the ESP8266 &amp;amp; Unix implementation of
MicroPython. The ESP8266 is an amazing device, considering it is the
size of a R5 coin and can run an implementation of Python. The talk will
cover features, limitations and some simple ideas to get going. A demo
of a simple Home Automation/IOT application with MicroPython &amp;amp; the
ESP8266 will also be included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk aims to bring the familiarity of Python 3 to developers, with
the hope of encouraging hack-a-day type projects without extensive
embedded device knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Christo Goosen</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-07:pycon-za-2016/micropython-python-for-microcontrollers-and-constrained-environments.html</guid><category>MicroPython</category></item></channel></rss>