<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_development.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Popping Kernels: An Exploration of Kernel Development for Jupyter Notebooks</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pydata-chicago-2016/popping-kernels-an-exploration-of-kernel-development-for-jupyter-notebooks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Safia Abdalla</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-26:pydata-chicago-2016/popping-kernels-an-exploration-of-kernel-development-for-jupyter-notebooks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Chicago 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will give individuals with no kernel experience and some Python experience, a brief introduction to the concepts they need to understand in order to develop kernels. This talk will also be useful to individuals who are looking for fun projects that will allow them to strengthen their skills in a particular programming language.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="development"></category><category term="jupyter"></category><category term="jupyter notebook"></category></entry><entry><title>Breaking down the process of building a custom CMS</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-2010/djangocon-2010--breaking-down-the-process-of-buil.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Brian Luft</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2010-09-07:djangocon-2010/djangocon-2010--breaking-down-the-process-of-buil.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this talk is to share some of the important insights
gained over a couple years of working on custom CMS-type projects
serving large organizations. Acknowledging that approx. 30 minutes is a
short time to cover a broad subject, the focus of the talk would be on
outlining a basic strategy for managing large projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past couple of years, Brian and Yann's team have built and
worked on several large Django projects for large organizations. They
will discuss how to start and manage large CMS projects, with an
emphasis on pointing people to the best reference information and
breaking down the common operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary discussion topics would cover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Breaking Down the Job: Over the course of the project you'll end up
accounting for thousands of details; here's how to figure out the
first few Centering Around a Prototype: Hedging your bets for the
inevitable &amp;quot;give me a ballpark figure&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dealing With Legacy Data Stores: Migrate legacy information early and
often.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selecting 3rd Party Components: Reuse exiting app, fork it early or
Trailblaze&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bad News: Django Ain't Perfect - where it has weaknesses and how to
compensate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of this talk the audience will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
* Break down this type of project into meaningful phases
* Migrate large dataset to populate the django models that are still under development.
* Have a rational and objective approach to select django reusable component and understand how to refine them during the different stages of the project lifecycle.
* Find and evaluate quality information about the tradeoffs Django presents in these types of projects
&lt;/pre&gt;
</summary><category term="development"></category><category term="djangocon"></category><category term="djangocon2010"></category><category term="projectmanagement"></category></entry><entry><title>The Development of Python and You</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--the-development-of-python-and-you.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Brian Curtin</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--the-development-of-python-and-you.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Development of Python and You&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Brian Curtin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have an inside look at what it takes to work on CPython, from getting
setup with the source and navigating the bug tracker, to the best
practices for having your work accepted. We'll find, categorize, and fix
an issue in Python to get you started. This talk is ideal for those who
are new to open source projects or are interested in the Python
development process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People from all backgrounds, users of all platforms, and developers of
all levels are necessary in the development of Python. From writing code
to documentation, it takes all kinds of people to make an impact. If
you've used Python, we need you, and what better place to get involved
than at PyCon?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2010 saw a rise in the number of contributors to CPython, and the PSF
stepped in to support the efforts of those wanting to get involved. Are
you up for the challenge? This talk dives right into what it takes to
get involved, covering the who, what, where, when, and why of Python
development, going through the whole process live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the conference is over, stick around with the CPython crew and
hack away!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="coredev"></category><category term="cpython"></category><category term="development"></category><category term="gettinginvolved"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2011"></category></entry></feed>