<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_networking.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2011-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>PyOhio 2010: Implementation of a Numerical Simulation in Python</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2010/pyohio-2010--implementation-of-a-numerical-simula.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>1990-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>1990-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jeffrey Armstrong</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,1990-01-01:pyohio-2010/pyohio-2010--implementation-of-a-numerical-simula.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Implementation of a Numerical Simulation in Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Jeffrey B. Armstrong&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Python programming language is well suited for numerical computation
under a variety of circumstances. Python offers advantages over
competing free and commercial technologies, including price,
functionality, and maintainability. Specifically, the combination of
mature numerical libraries and liberal licensing allow complex
simulations to be coded with ease and to be made available to nearly all
interested parties. !NumPy/!SciPy, database access, networking, and
optimization techniques are examined in detail with respect to numerical
computation. A practical example involving an aerothermal commercial
turbofan aircraft engine simulation showcases these advantages. An
aircraft engine is broken down into discrete stages, including
compressors, turbines, and other flow-related components. Commonalities
between components, such as rotation and the presence of inlet and exit
conditions, map cleanly to the object-oriented nature of Python. Based
on simulation needs and hardware availability, Python allows for the
parallel computation of simulations without the expense and complexity
of commercial parallelization packages.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="database"></category><category term="networking"></category><category term="numpy"></category><category term="optimization"></category><category term="pyohio"></category><category term="pyohio2010"></category><category term="scipy"></category><category term="simulation"></category></entry><entry><title>Social Network Analysis in Python</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/social-network-analysis-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Enrico Franchi</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-13:europython-2011/social-network-analysis-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Enrico Franchi - 23 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Lasagne&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Network Analysis has gained a huge recognition since the widespread
adoption of on-line social networking systems. It is a
cross-disciplinary subject with important contributions from researchers
of different areas such as physics, sociology, maths and computer
science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Network Analysis is also a useful tool for the working
programmer. The basic techniques which will be introduced in this talk
can be used, for example, both to i) test the robustness and resilience
to damage of a technological network and ii) understand the structure of
a social network, which can in turn lead to insight on trends and
preferences gathering information from modern on-line social networking
systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with the concepts, working Python code is presented, both using
existing network analysis Python tools and numeric packages. The focus
is mainly placed on code, which will be shown and discussed together
with the formal theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basic maths skills and basic knowledge of the Python programming
language are the only suggested prerequisites.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="analysis"></category><category term="network"></category><category term="networking"></category></entry><entry><title>Networking Libraries in Python</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2011/networking-libraries-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Senthil Kumuran</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-08-22:pycon-au-2011/networking-libraries-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will explore the core networking libraries available in
Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python Standard Library. http and urllib package (Python3 and
Python2).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Capabilities of other 3rd party networking libraries - pycurl and
httplib2. When to use them and why they exist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Asychronous Network IO using Twisted Matrix Framework.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tornado framework capablities - Generic overview.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</summary><category term="framework"></category><category term="network"></category><category term="networking"></category><category term="pycurl"></category><category term="tornado"></category><category term="twisted"></category><category term="urllib"></category></entry></feed>