<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_diversity.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Django Girls</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycaribbean-2016/pycaribbean-2016-django-girls-ola-sitarska.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ola Sitarska</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-02-20:pycaribbean-2016/pycaribbean-2016-django-girls-ola-sitarska.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><category term="keynote"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="django girls"></category><category term="diversity"></category></entry><entry><title>Building a More Inclusive Python Community Culture</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pytexas-2015/building-a-more-inclusive-python-community-cultur.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kojo Idrissa</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-09:pytexas-2015/building-a-more-inclusive-python-community-cultur.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Groups that are more diverse are &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.google.com/#q=diverse+%22problem+solving%22"&gt;better at solving
problems&lt;/a&gt;
than more homogenous groups. An inclusive group culture maximizes the
odds of attracting and retaining skills &amp;amp; personalities needed to
thrive. The Python community has a pretty good track record on issues
related to inclusion. So, how can you help continue that trend,
especially in your local community? I'll start with a brief &lt;em&gt;WHY&lt;/em&gt; and
&lt;em&gt;WHAT&lt;/em&gt; of Inclusion, but most of this talk focuses on &lt;strong&gt;HOW&lt;/strong&gt; to help
your local corner of the Python community be as Inclusive as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="inclusion"></category><category term="diversity"></category><category term="Community"></category><category term="Culture"></category></entry><entry><title>Diversity as a Dependency</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/diversity-as-a-dependency.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Anna Ravenscroft</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-21:europython-2011/diversity-as-a-dependency.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Anna Ravenscroft - 20 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Spaghetti&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The PSF recently adopted a diversity statement. While some argue that we
should do this just because it's &amp;quot;the right thing to do&amp;quot;, others
question why we, as a technical community, should even worry about
diversity. This talk addresses the diversity question, not in moralistic
or ethical terms, but in pragmatic ones. Studies on creativity and
productivity demonstrate the potential benefits of diversity for the
Python community. Making Python the best language it can be is not
merely helped by increasing diversity, but may be dependent on
diversity.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="diversity"></category><category term="psf"></category></entry><entry><title>Diversity in Tech: Improving our Toolset</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--diversity-in-tech--improving-our-tool.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jennifer Leech</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--diversity-in-tech--improving-our-tool.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Diversity in Tech: Improving our Toolset&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Jennifer Leech&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As communities allow more diversity, they draw from a larger talent
pool, challenge each other more, and hit a higher bar in terms of
ingenuity and work-product. However questions surrounding diversity
often seem under- examined. What are the effects of diversity in the
community, or lack thereof? I intend to approach this topic from an
accessible and entertaining, yet analytical perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year there was a photo of Kate Moss shown during a PyCon
presentation which raised debate as to its appropriateness. This debate
brought up some interesting questions - but what I found most
interesting was that while it elicited strong opinions, the issue seemed
to be somewhat unexamined. This event sparked a desire for deeper
analysis on this topic in a more focussed setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I intend to address some of the core principles underlying
this debate. Discussion will include the following questions: Where does
responsibility lie in understanding these issues? What are the effects
of failing to do so? What are the effects of diversity in the community,
or lack thereof? What do we lose by being more homogenous or more
diverse? Gain?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As communities allow more diversity, they draw from a larger talent
pool, challenge each other more, and hit a higher bar in terms of
ingenuity and work-product. However, diversity requires awareness and
tolerance on both the part of the dominant culture and on the part of
the new arrivals to smooth the inevitable rough edges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I intend to approach this topic from an accessible, inclusive and
entertaining, yet analytical perspective. The broader intent is to raise
the level of understanding and community discourse on this topic. It is
odd that diversity can so dramatically affect our lives and communities
and yet be unexamined, particularly in a community so highly intelligent
and educated as that which populates the tech industry.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="diversity"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2011"></category></entry><entry><title>Get new contributors (and diversity) through outreach</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--get-new-contributors--and-diversity--.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Asheesh Laroia</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--get-new-contributors--and-diversity--.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get new contributors (and diversity) through outreach&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Asheesh Laroia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Groups like the Fedora Design Team, Dreamwidth, SF Ruby, and OpenHatch
have discovered the power of outreach to bring in new contributors. In
the past year, SF Ruby grew in numbers as well as in diversity, moving
from 3% women to 18% women. Because most projects need ongoing help,
this talk discusses effective strategies for bringing in contributors
who stick around for the long haul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is targeted at anyone involved in an open source project who
wants to find more contributors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programs like Google Summer of Code often provide excited students who
disappear after a summer's work. Meanwhile, request for help emails on
development lists are typically met with silence. Hackathons create a
flurry of commits, but then we never hear from the participants again.
Expanding your team is possible, and it requires care in terms of
outreach, expectation management, and mentorship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will discuss three major forms of outreach:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One-on-one check-ins with participants,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Periodic drives to bring in new contributors, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In-person teaching events. Each one has &amp;quot;do&amp;quot;s and &amp;quot;don't&amp;quot;s associated
with it. This talk digests the experience of effective outreach into
practical strategies that you can re-use within your project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="diversity"></category><category term="openhatch"></category><category term="outreach"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2011"></category></entry></feed>