<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_business.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2011-07-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>PyOhio 2010: Python and Entrepreneurship</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2010/pyohio-2010--python-and-entrepreneurship.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>1990-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>1990-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Unknown</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,1990-01-01:pyohio-2010/pyohio-2010--python-and-entrepreneurship.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python and Entrepeneurship&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Featuring Eric Floehr, Nick Albright, Matt Wilson, Austin Godber, James
Bonanno&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the strengths of dynamic languages is rapid development and quick
results. Python has been used by a number of Ohio small businesses, from
supporting back-office operations to being the language the company's
products are built on. This panel discussion will talk about the
opportunities and challenges in using Python to build a business on, as
well as a discussion on starting, running, and growing a
technology-based business.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="business"></category><category term="entrepeneur"></category><category term="pyohio"></category><category term="pyohio2010"></category></entry><entry><title>Pricing products using Python graphs and sets</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/pricing-products-using-python-graphs-and-sets.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Rob Collins</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-21:europython-2011/pricing-products-using-python-graphs-and-sets.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Rob Collins - 22 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Ravioli &amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We will look at the limitations of available rule engines when it comes
to complex pricing rules. Rob has been part of a Python team writing a
pricing engine based on network graphs. We will show:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why pricing is not easy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rule engine anti-patterns, e.g. to change one price requires a week's
development time, and has to be fitted into a release cycle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to make pricing rules data driven, usable by the business&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How the use of graphs and sets reduces the complexity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rob is joined by David Layton of Grey Squirrel Consulting, who is a
fellow contractor working with Rob on the pricing project. He is an
American expatriate and Python developer, currently living and working
in London. His background is in scientific computing, CRMs and Business
Intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="business"></category><category term="graphs"></category><category term="network"></category><category term="scientific"></category></entry><entry><title>Getting ready for PostgreSQL 9.1</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/getting-ready-for-postgresql-91.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Gabriele Bartolini</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-13:europython-2011/getting-ready-for-postgresql-91.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Gabriele Bartolini,Harald Armin Massa,Marco Nenciarini
- 22 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Training Pizza Napoli &amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PostgreSQL is an advanced, versatile open-source database management
system that integrates perfectly with Python. It is developed by a very
active international community and is distributed under the BSD-like
PostgreSQL License.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enterprise-class features (including SQL standard compliance, ACID
transactions, disaster recovery, high availability, replication,
partitioning and general extensibility) make PostgreSQL suitable for
business critical environments seeking to reduce the TCO of their
database solutions without altering their functional needs. PostgreSQL
9.0, released in September 2010, was the first version of PostgreSQL
with Hot Standby, a built-in master/slave replication mechanism.
Asynchronous replication through the standard and consolidated log
shipping technique (previously used with Warm Standby for high
availability) has been enhanced with streaming replication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Version 9.1, expected to be out later in 2011, will add synchronous
replication to PostgreSQL, making it the first DBMS that allows
developers and users to control the replication strategy at
transactional granularity. Come to the talk and discover all the major
new features of PostgreSQL 9.1, including extensions management,
writable common table expressions (WCTE), etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="asynchronous"></category><category term="business"></category><category term="community"></category><category term="database"></category><category term="distributed"></category><category term="extensions"></category><category term="partitioning"></category><category term="postgresql"></category><category term="replication"></category></entry><entry><title>OpenERP: 100% pythonic way for business management</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/openerp-100-pythonic-way-for-business-managemen.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Davide Corio</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-13:europython-2011/openerp-100-pythonic-way-for-business-managemen.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Davide Corio - 23 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Tagliatelle&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Business management isn't just accounting. Let's see how Python can help
us to build a complete ERP infrastructure. From CRM to e-commerce, from
accounting to document management…we'll see how Python is mature and
able to do great things where Java and .NET are still considered as the
only option. Case studies to be presented.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="business"></category><category term="crm"></category><category term="java"></category><category term=".net"></category></entry><entry><title>PostgreSQL - the database-sister of Python</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/postgresql-the-database-sister-of-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Harald Armin Massa</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-13:europython-2011/postgresql-the-database-sister-of-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Harald Armin Massa - 21 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Lasagne&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk is the updated and especially enhanced of the &amp;quot;Python and
PostgreSQL - a match made in heaven&amp;quot; talk of EP 2006, CERN, Switzerland.
PostgreSQL and Python share more then the first letter: their
communities have great similiarities; their development processes are
really comparable; their licenses and their openness to academics AND
business (on a technical and communitie perspective) are big pluses. We
will have a look at those similiarities and learn why PostgreSQL is
really the database sister to Python. There will be an overview of
PostgreSQL, information of how to connect PostgreSQL and Python; how
PostgreSQL streaming replication works and what it can do for you, how
PL/Python helps to have Web 2.5 JSON storage and handling right inside
PostgreSQL. We will show that YESQL is also a valid answer to many data
storage qeuestions.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="business"></category><category term="database"></category><category term="json"></category><category term="postgresql"></category><category term="replication"></category><category term="web"></category></entry><entry><title>Serious Business: Python is not just for Engineering</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--serious-business--python-is-not-just-.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Zach Steindler</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--serious-business--python-is-not-just-.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Serious Business: Python is not just for Engineering&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Zach Steindler&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building a great business is quite different from building a great
product, but by measuring Key Performance Indicators (things like cash
flow, if users keep coming back, etc.) you can make sure your business
is on the right track. In this talk I'll cover common KPI in the tech
business and show you how we automate collecting and presenting KPI at
Olark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a hacker-turned-founder, you quickly realize there's more to building
a great business than just building a great product. The easiest way to
know your business is on the right track is to measure Key Performance
Indicators (KPIs): things like cash flow, what parts of the product is
used the most, if your users keep coming back, if users are experiencing
problems... and many, many others. How are you supposed to keep track of
it all without getting lost in a sea of noise?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Python, of course! In this talk I'll cover the most common KPIs
technology businesses track and show you how we used Python at Olark to
automatically collect and present KPIs to the team. This has made it
much easier to quickly answer business questions and help us know we're
on the right track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you're a Python hacker who would like to learn more about how to
engineer a business, or if you're a business person who's just starting
to learn Python, come learn how Python isn't just for engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="business"></category><category term="kpi"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2011"></category></entry></feed>