<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_mock.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Testing with mock</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--testing-with-mock.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Michael Foord</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--testing-with-mock.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Testing with mock&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Michael Foord&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mock is a Python testing library. It has the goal of making mocking in
tests brain dead simple! mock provides the Mock class and the patch
decorator for safely patching out the objects you are mocking in your
tests. This talk will cover standard mocking patterns. We'll also look
at some of the newer features in the latest release, including support
for mocking magic methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mock provides a core Mock class that removes the need to create a host
of trivial stubs throughout your test suite. After performing an action,
you can make assertions about which methods / attributes were used and
arguments they were called with. You can also specify return values and
set specific attributes in the normal way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.voidspace.org.uk/python/mock/"&gt;http://www.voidspace.org.uk/python/mock/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pypi.python.org/pypi/mock/"&gt;http://pypi.python.org/pypi/mock/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mock module also provides a patch() decorator that handles safely
patching out the things you are mocking during your test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll cover standard mocking patterns, and how mock makes them easy.
We'll also be looking at some of the newer features in the latest
release, including the magic method support that can be used (for
example) for mocking out objects used as context managers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mock is designed for &amp;quot;unit test style&amp;quot; testing, but is used with Python
testing libraries like nose and py.test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be some emphasis on how &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to use mocking in testing, and
why 'over mocking' is bad (and makes for brittle tests).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="mock"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2011"></category><category term="testing"></category></entry></feed>