<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Python Blockchain and Byte-Size Change</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pydx-2016/python-blockchain-and-byte-size-change.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyDX 2016 keynote by Portia Burton&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will answer the question of what is bitcoin and the blockchain and will end with a quick tutorial on how to create a blockchain application in Flask. We will not only make a bitcoin application, but we will also reflect upon the implications of this cutting edge technology to the greater society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin and blockchain technology has been in the news as of late, such as the hard fork of Ethereum to the hack of Bitifnex. This talk will cover the basics of blockchain technology and we will learn how to build an application that accepts bitcoin. Armed with a little knowledge of Flask and REST we will be able to use Python to bridge the gap between current events and technology. As Python developers we will be able to add to the narrative of bitcoin/blockchain technology in a unique and meaningful way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Portia Burton</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-12-30:pydx-2016/python-blockchain-and-byte-size-change.html</guid><category>bitcoin</category><category>blockchain</category></item><item><title>PyOhio 2011: Exchange Digital Money using Bitcoin</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2011/pyohio-2011--exchange-digital-money-using-bitcoin.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Exchange Digital Money Using Bitcoin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by David Steele&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin is described as the first decentralized digital currency. This
talk describes how Bitcoin uses public key encryption, proof-of-work
based logging, and peer-to-peer technology to create a type of money
which can be transferred over the Internet. We'll cover how to use
Python to manage your digital wallet and participate in this new P2P
economy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">David Steele</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 1990 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,1990-01-01:pyohio-2011/pyohio-2011--exchange-digital-money-using-bitcoin.html</guid><category>bitcoin</category><category>pyohio</category><category>pyohio2011</category></item></channel></rss>