<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_flask.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>It's Raining, It's Pouring? A web and SMS application in Flask and Twilio to call Farmers.</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pygotham-2016/its-raining-its-pouring-a-web-and-sms-application-in-flask-and-twilio-to-call-farmers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Katya Vasilaky</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-16:pygotham-2016/its-raining-its-pouring-a-web-and-sms-application-in-flask-and-twilio-to-call-farmers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk is about the use of python in building a web application with which we call farmers in less developed countries to capture rainfall occurrence. These data are used to complement lower resolution satellite data, and to potentially update climate models. The application is built in Flask and uses Twilio's API to deliver voicemails to farmers in less developed countries. Twilio's API records farmers' touch tone responses regarding the occurrence of rainfall.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="flask"></category></entry><entry><title>Fifty shades of docker</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-es-2014/fifty-shades-of-docker.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ivan Pedrazas</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-04-06:pycon-es-2014/fifty-shades-of-docker.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;El workshop intentara explicar como montar una application hecha en Flask que usa un cluster de Cassandra (o mongo o redis... la base de datos da un poco igual) como backend y tiene servicios anyadidos como podria ser un buscador (ES)&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="workshop"></category><category term="flask"></category><category term="cassandra"></category></entry><entry><title>PyOhio 2011: Django and Google App Engine: Why I'm using Flask and Amazon EC2</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pyohio-2011/pyohio-2011--django-and-google-app-engine--why-i-.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>1990-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>1990-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Ben Rousch</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,1990-01-01:pyohio-2011/pyohio-2011--django-and-google-app-engine--why-i-.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Django and Google App Engine: Why I'm Using Flask and Amazon EC2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Ben Rousch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm a lazy coder, but not the good kind of lazy. I dove into Django so I
could have one web framework that would work on many kind of hosting
setups and for any kind of web project. With some modifications, I could
even use the laziest application host, Google App Engine. Some of these
decisions didn't work out, so I'll share some of the lessons I've
learned the past year or so.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="ec2"></category><category term="flask"></category><category term="gae"></category><category term="googleappengine"></category><category term="pyohio"></category><category term="pyohio2011"></category></entry><entry><title>Flasky Goodness (or Why Django Sucks?)</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-2012/flasky-goodness-or-why-django-sucks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Kenneth Reitz</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2012-09-05:djangocon-2012/flasky-goodness-or-why-django-sucks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk dives into the specifics of why Django isn't always the best
tool for the job, general frustrations with the framework, and potential
fixes. It will balance out with many Django praises too, of course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk dives into the specifics of why Django isn't always the best
tool for the job, general frustrations with the framework, and potential
fixes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will balance out with many Django praises too, of course.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="flask"></category></entry><entry><title>An iPhone-Python love affair: Building APIs for mobile</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/an-iphone-python-love-affair-building-apis-for-m.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Anna Callahan</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-07:europython-2011/an-iphone-python-love-affair-building-apis-for-m.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Anna Callahan,Nate Aune - 24 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track
Spaghetti&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mobile apps are the hot item of the day - and the best mobile apps are
backed by a great website. Python web developer Nate Aune and iPhone
developer Anna Callahan will show you how we built a simple music web
app in Django with a native iPhone app that communicates with it.
Attendees of this talk will see a concrete case study of building an
application that exposes an API for mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our web app exposes a JSON API for sending and receiving data from the
mobile device. We’ll talk about why we chose Django and the TastyPie API
package, and discuss other Python-based frameworks that could be used to
build the API such as Pyramid, Flask and Bottle. We’ll also compare REST
and custom APIs to understand best practices for building APIs designed
for mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="api"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="flask"></category><category term="json"></category><category term="mobile"></category><category term="rest"></category><category term="tastypie"></category><category term="web"></category></entry><entry><title>Opening the Flask</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--opening-the-flask.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Armin Ronacher</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2011-03-11:pycon-us-2011/pycon-2011--opening-the-flask.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Opening the Flask&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Armin Ronacher&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a year of the Flask microframework it's time to draw some
conclusions, see things that went right and things that should be
improved. The talk gives both an introduction into Flask itself as well
as well as the ecosystem that evolved around it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flask is a microframework that was born out of an April's fool joke that
quickly became more than that. Based on the powerful foundation of
Werkzeug and Jinja2 it's one of the most popular frameworks for Python
now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk starts with a very quick introduction into Flask, where it all
started and why I think people like it. We will look into the design of
Flask and why it works the way it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore we will look into the Flask ecosystem and how extensions
work and have a brief look in what is planned for the future, especially
regarding Python 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk assumes basic knowledge of web applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="flask"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="pycon2011"></category></entry></feed>