<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Deploying Django</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/djangocon-2009/djangocon-2009--deploying-django.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deploying Django&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by Brian Rosner&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talks about deploying django sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[VIDEO HAS ISSUES: mostly in left speaker]&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Brian Rosner</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2009-09-08:djangocon-2009/djangocon-2009--deploying-django.html</guid><category>deploy</category><category>deployment</category><category>djangocon</category><category>djangocon2009</category></item><item><title>Data Driven Cache Invalidation</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/data-driven-cache-invalidation.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Magnus Hagander - 23 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Ravioli&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In todays world, nobody (should) deploy a web application facing the
internet without having a proper caching system in place. There are many
different solutions to choose from, from manual use of memcached through
framework integrated caching to external caches like Squid or Varnish.
Most modern frameworks come with integrated functionality for at least
one of these methods, and often more than one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, they often relies on all traffic going through the same
framework to work properly - a caching layer in Rails is hard to share
with one in Django. This talk will show a way to break the design rules
of these frameworks just a little, and have the database help solve this
problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will use a small application written in Python using Django to
illustrate the examples, but the method is language independent.
Unsurprisingly, the database used is PostgreSQL.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Magnus Hagander</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-24:europython-2011/data-driven-cache-invalidation.html</guid><category>cache</category><category>database</category><category>deploy</category><category>design</category><category>django</category><category>framework</category><category>web</category></item><item><title>Deploying web applications to the cloud with Python</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/deploying-web-applications-to-the-cloud-with-pyth.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Nate Aune - 23 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Ravioli&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How can Python help you deploy web applications to the cloud? Amazon EC2
provides virtual machines on demand but as a developer you still have to
configure these machines and push your code to them. Fabric is a Python
library that lets you execute commands on a remote machine, and Boto is
a Python library for interfacing with Amazon web services. By using
Fabric and Boto, you can easily create repeatable deployments and
provision new resources as needed with minimal effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will introduce Amazon Web Services and how to launch new
machines using simple Boto scripts, and how to get started making your
own repeatable deployments using Fabric scripts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nate Aune</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-24:europython-2011/deploying-web-applications-to-the-cloud-with-pyth.html</guid><category>boto</category><category>cloud</category><category>deploy</category><category>ec2</category><category>fabric</category><category>web</category></item><item><title>Best Practices for Python in the Cloud</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/best-practices-for-python-in-the-cloud.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Gisle Aas - 21 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Lasagne&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Abstract: Whether you’re an independent developer or development manager
in a large company, “the cloud” is on everyone’s mind. But just because
it’s in the cloud, doesn’t mean development and deployment is
effortless. The cloud presents infrastructure and development challenges
in a new way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this presentation, ActiveState's Gisle Aas will share best practices
in building and deploying a Python-centric LAMP stack(s) on the cloud
for a range of web-based applications from simple Django site to HPC GPU
Clusters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on ActiveState’s experiences, Gisle will discuss the challenges
faced and lessons learned in building an infrastructure to deploy web
applications to the cloud with Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will learn about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which packages are critical for a secure, Python-centric LAMP stack
(and what it takes to build them)!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tips for developing, deploying, and scaling Python applicaitons in
the cloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to use Python to connect and build infrastructure to support and
manage your deployment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Gisle Aas</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-18:europython-2011/best-practices-for-python-in-the-cloud.html</guid><category>cloud</category><category>deploy</category><category>deployment</category><category>django</category><category>gpu</category><category>hpc</category><category>infrastructure</category><category>lamp</category><category>packages</category><category>scaling</category><category>web</category></item><item><title>Developing a Cad application as an hobby. My exciting hobby is now my job</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/developing-a-cad-application-as-an-hobby-my-exci.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Matteo Boscolo - 22 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Tagliatelle &amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PythonCAD is a CAD package written, surprisingly enough, in Python using
the PyQt interface. The PythonCAD project aims to produce a scriptable,
open- source, easy to use CAD package for Linux (Cross Platforms).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I start developing PythonCAD in my spare time and now python is the
programming language that I mostly use. I think that will be very
interesting to tell my story and how I learn python pyqt ,sqlite, sympy…
and how python and pycon and OpenERP change my job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal will be to tell at the new python programmer how easy to use is
python even for complex problem. I can explain why I chose pyqt .. what
kind of trouble I have found and how I solve it. Starting from python
going to pyqt and at the end how to deploy a python application with
pyInstaller …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also explain my actual project OpenPLM an OpenERP module to manage PLM
data into OpenERP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;see you soon Matteo&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Matteo Boscolo</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-13:europython-2011/developing-a-cad-application-as-an-hobby-my-exci.html</guid><category>deploy</category><category>pycon</category><category>pyqt</category></item><item><title>uWSGI, il coltellino svizzero (di MacGyver) del deploy</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/europython-2011/uwsgi-il-coltellino-svizzero-di-macgyver-del-d.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[EuroPython 2011] Roberto De Ioris - 21 June 2011 in &amp;quot;Track Italiana Big
Mac&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;La prima parte del talk introdurra' la storia di uWSGI, dall'idea
iniziale alla messa in produzione dei primi lavori, fino alla sua
inclusione nei progetti Cherokee e Nginx.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seguira' una serie di esempi di deploy in ambienti ostili (a livello di
sicurezza, non faremo deploy nella jungla) o con risorse fortemente
limitate fino all'utilizzo delle funzionalita' integrate per il
clustering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il talk si rivolge a tutti gli sviluppatori di applicazioni web che sono
alla ricerca di un ambiente robusto e veloce per i propri lavori, o a
chi gia' utilizza uWSGI e vuole conoscere qualcuna delle nuove
funzionalita' introdotte nel ramo di sviluppo.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Roberto De Ioris</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-07-13:europython-2011/uwsgi-il-coltellino-svizzero-di-macgyver-del-d.html</guid><category>deploy</category><category>web</category></item><item><title>How to maintain big app stacks without losing your mind</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pycon-au-2011/how-to-maintain-big-app-stacks-without-losing-you.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;zc.buildout is a powerful build/configure/deployment tool for creating
applications from multiple parts, some not python. It's perfect for
sharing a development environment or deploy applications to many hosts.
This tutorial will cover basic concepts, similarity to other tools such
as virtual-env, puppet etc as well as practical examples. zc.buildout
has successful been used with web applications such as Plone, django and
pyramid.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dylan Jay</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2011-08-22:pycon-au-2011/how-to-maintain-big-app-stacks-without-losing-you.html</guid><category>deploy</category><category>django</category><category>puppet</category><category>tutorial</category><category>web</category><category>zc.buildout</category></item></channel></rss>