<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>PyVideo.org</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Making your code faster: Cython and parallel processing in the Jupyter Notebook</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pydata-dc-2016/making-your-code-faster-cython-and-parallel-processing-in-the-jupyter-notebook.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData DC 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Github: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/gapatino/Making-Your-Code-Faster-Cython-and-parallel-processing-in-the-Jupyter-Notebook"&gt;https://github.com/gapatino/Making-Your-Code-Faster-Cython-and-parallel-processing-in-the-Jupyter-Notebook&lt;/a&gt;
Slides: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.slideshare.net/PyData/making-your-code-faster-cython-and-parallel-processing-in-the-jupyter-notebook"&gt;http://www.slideshare.net/PyData/making-your-code-faster-cython-and-parallel-processing-in-the-jupyter-notebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the complexity and scope of applications grow, it is very common to run into slow performance issues. In Python, it is possible to improve the speed of execution with the use of parallel processing and the Cython compiler. The Jupyter Notebook makes the implementation of both of them a relatively simple task, which will be the focus of this session.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Gustavo Patino</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-10-09:pydata-dc-2016/making-your-code-faster-cython-and-parallel-processing-in-the-jupyter-notebook.html</guid><category>code</category><category>Cython</category><category>jupyter</category><category>jupyter notebook</category><category>notebook</category><category>parallel</category><category>processing</category></item><item><title>Popping Kernels: An Exploration of Kernel Development for Jupyter Notebooks</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/pydata-chicago-2016/popping-kernels-an-exploration-of-kernel-development-for-jupyter-notebooks.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Chicago 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will give individuals with no kernel experience and some Python experience, a brief introduction to the concepts they need to understand in order to develop kernels. This talk will also be useful to individuals who are looking for fun projects that will allow them to strengthen their skills in a particular programming language.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Safia Abdalla</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-08-26:pydata-chicago-2016/popping-kernels-an-exploration-of-kernel-development-for-jupyter-notebooks.html</guid><category>development</category><category>jupyter</category><category>jupyter notebook</category></item><item><title>Diffing and Merging Jupyter Notebooks with nbdime</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/scipy-2016/diffing-and-merging-jupyter-notebooks-with-nbdime-scipy-2016-min-ragan-kelley.html</link><description></description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Min Ragan Kelley</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-15:scipy-2016/diffing-and-merging-jupyter-notebooks-with-nbdime-scipy-2016-min-ragan-kelley.html</guid><category>SciPy 2016</category><category>jupyter</category><category>jupyter notebook</category></item><item><title>JupyterLab: Building Blocks for Interactive Computing</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/scipy-2016/jupyterlab-building-blocks-for-interactive-computing-scipy-2016-brian-granger.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Project Jupyter provides building blocks for interactive and exploratory computing. These building blocks make science and data science reproducible across over 40 programming language (Python, Julia, R, etc.). Central to the project is the Jupyter Notebook, a web-based interactive computing platform that allows users to author data- and code-driven narratives - computational narratives - that combine live code, equations, narrative text, visualizations, interactive dashboards and other media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the Jupyter Notebook has proved to be an incredibly productive way of working with code and data interactively, it is helpful to decompose notebooks into more primitive building blocks: kernels for code execution, input areas for typing code, markdown cells for composing narrative content, output areas for showing results, terminals, etc. The fundamental idea of JupyterLab is to offer a user interface that allows users to assemble these building blocks in different ways to support interactive workflows that include, but go far beyond, Jupyter Notebooks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JupyterLab accomplishes this by providing a modular and extensible user interface that exposes these building blocks in the context of a powerful work space. Users can arrange multiple notebooks, text editors, terminals, output areas, etc. on a single page with multiple panels, tabs, splitters, and collapsible sidebars with a file browser, command palette and integrated help system. The codebase and UI of JupyterLab is based on a flexible plugin system that makes it easy to extend with new components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we will demonstrate the JupyterLab interface, its codebase, and describe how it fits within the overall roadmap of the project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Brian Granger</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-15:scipy-2016/jupyterlab-building-blocks-for-interactive-computing-scipy-2016-brian-granger.html</guid><category>SciPy 2016</category><category>jupyter</category><category>jupyterlab</category><category>jupyter notebook</category></item><item><title>Keynote: Project Jupyter</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/scipy-2016/keynote-project-jupyter-scipy-2016-brian-granger.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Brian Granger is an Associate Professor of Physics at Cal Poly State University in San Luis Obispo, CA. He has a background in theoretical physics, with a Ph.D from the University of Colorado. His current research interests include quantum computing, parallel and distributed computing and interactive computing environments for scientific computing and data science. He is a leader of the IPython project, co-founder of Project Jupyter and is an active contributor to a number of other open source projects focused on data science in Python. He is a board member of the NumFocus Foundation and a fellow at Cal Poly’s Center for Innovation and Entrepreneurship. He is &amp;#64;ellisonbg on Twitter and GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Announcement of Altair, Altair is a declarative statistical visualization library for Python. Altair is developed by Brian Granger and Jake Vanderplas in close collaboration with the UW Interactive Data Lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Altair, you can spend more time understanding your data and its meaning. Altair's API is simple, friendly and consistent and built on top of the powerful Vega-Lite JSON specification. This elegant simplicity produces beautiful and effective visualizations with a minimal amount of code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Brian Granger</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-15:scipy-2016/keynote-project-jupyter-scipy-2016-brian-granger.html</guid><category>SciPy 2016</category><category>altair</category><category>jupyter</category><category>jupyter notebook</category></item><item><title>Proselint: The Linting of Science Prose, and the Science of Prose Linting</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/scipy-2016/proselint-the-linting-of-science-prose-and-the-science-of-prose-linting-scipy-2016-michael-pac.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Writing is notoriously hard, even for the best writers, and it's not for lack of good advice — a tremendous amount of knowledge is strewn across usage guides, dictionaries, technical manuals, essays, pamphlets, websites, and the hearts and minds of great authors and editors. But this knowledge is trapped, waiting to be extracted and transformed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We built Proselint, a Python-based linter for prose. Proselint identifies violations of expert style and usage guidelines. Proselint is open-source software released under the BSD license and works with Python 2 and 3. It runs as a command-line utility or editor plugin (e.g., Sublime Text, Atom, Vim, Emacs) and outputs advice in standard formats (e.g., JSON). Though in its infancy – perhaps 2% of what it could be – Proselint already includes modules addressing: redundancy, jargon, illogic, clichés, sexism, misspelling, inconsistency, misuse of symbols, malapropisms, oxymorons, security gaffes, hedging, apologizing, pretension.     Proselint can be seen as both a language tool for scientists and a tool for language science. On the one hand, it includes modules that promote clear and consistent prose in science writing. On the other, it measures language usage and explores the factors relevant to creating a useful linter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Michael Pacer</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-15:scipy-2016/proselint-the-linting-of-science-prose-and-the-science-of-prose-linting-scipy-2016-michael-pac.html</guid><category>SciPy 2016</category><category>lint</category><category>prose</category><category>jupyter</category></item><item><title>JupyterHub as an Interactive Supercomputing Gateway</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/scipy-2016/jupyterhub-as-an-interactive-supercomputing-gateway-scipy-2016-michael-milligan.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the Minnesota Supercomputing Institute we are exploring ways to provide the immediacy and flexibility of interactive computing within the batch-scheduled, tightly controlled world of traditional cluster supercomputing. As Jupyter Notebook has gained in popularity, the steps needed to use it within such an environment have proven to be a barrier to entry even as increasingly powerful Python tools have developed to take advantage of large computational resources. JupyterHub to the rescue! Except out of the box, it doesn't know anything about resource types, job submission, and so on. We developed BatchSpawner and friends as a general JupyterHub backend for batch-scheduled environments. In this talk I will walk through how we have deployed JupyterHub to provide a user-friendly gateway to interactive supercomputing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Michael Milligan</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-14:scipy-2016/jupyterhub-as-an-interactive-supercomputing-gateway-scipy-2016-michael-milligan.html</guid><category>SciPy 2016</category><category>hpc</category><category>jupyterhub</category><category>jupyter</category><category>jupyter notebook</category><category>supercomputing</category></item><item><title>Reproducible, One Button Workflows with the Jupyter Notebook &amp; Scons</title><link>http://pyvideo.org/scipy-2016/reproducible-one-button-workflows-with-the-jupyter-notebook-scons-scipy-2016-jessica-hamrick.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is the best way to develop analysis code in the Jupyter notebook, while managing complex dependencies between analyses? In this talk, I will introduce nbflow, which is a project that integrates a Python-based build system (SCons) with the Jupyter notebook, enabling researchers to easily build sophisticated,
complex analysis pipelines entirely within notebooks while still maintaining a &amp;quot;one-button workflow&amp;quot; in which all analyses can be executed, in the correct order, from a single command. I will show how nbflow can be applied to existing analyses and how it can be used to construct an analysis pipeline stretching the entire way from data cleaning, to computing statistics, to generating figures,
and even to automatically generating LaTeX commands that can be used in publications to format results without the risk of copy-and-paste error.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jessica Hamrick</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:pyvideo.org,2016-07-14:scipy-2016/reproducible-one-button-workflows-with-the-jupyter-notebook-scons-scipy-2016-jessica-hamrick.html</guid><category>SciPy 2016</category><category>jupyter</category><category>jupyter notebook</category><category>workflow</category><category>nbflow</category></item></channel></rss>