<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyVideo.org</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pyvideo.org/feeds/tag_bokeh.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pyvideo.org/</id><updated>2016-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Networks meet Finance in Python</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pydata-amsterdam-2016/networks-meet-finance-in-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Miguel Vaz</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-03-26:pydata-amsterdam-2016/networks-meet-finance-in-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PyData Amsterdam 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will talk about network models in finance, and walk through real data and very visual examples using the pydata toolset - pandas, bokeh, pandas, networkx, ipywidgets. Special focus will be given to correlation networks, with applications to market characterization and portfolio risk management (as done in Pozzi 2013) using the latest available market data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the course of the 2008 Lehman and the subsequent European debt crisis, it became clear that both financial industry and regulators had underestimated the degree of interconnectedness and interdependency across financial assets and institutions. This type of information is especially well represented by network models, which had first gained popularity in computer science, biology and social sciences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study of network models in finance is already providing insight into the structure of the financial world and the economy. Network models are proving to be useful tools for providing early-warning signals of systemic risk (e.g. Squartini 2013), measuring liquidity and concentration risk, identifying sectors from time-series correlations (e.g. Fenn 2011) as well as insights into finding diversified baskets of assets in the classical investment framework (e.g. Pozzi 2013).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will provide an overview of some of the aforementioned work, and walk through (real data) examples using the pydata toolset. Special focus will be given to the study of correlation networks, with applications to portfolio risk management as in (Pozzi 2013) using the latest available market data. The examples make heavy use of pandas, bokeh, pandas, networkx, ipywidgets.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pandas"></category><category term="bokeh"></category><category term="networkx"></category><category term="ipywidgets"></category></entry><entry><title>¡Eureka! (Python y ciencia)</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pyday-galicia-2016/eureka-python-y-ciencia.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Miguel Sánchez de León Peque</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-09-17:pyday-galicia-2016/eureka-python-y-ciencia.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;En esta charla se plantea una pregunta de física básica que se resolverá científicamente con ingenio, mátemáticas y python, aprovechando para (de una manera amena) ver librerías habituales en el entorno científico como sympy, numpy, scipy, matplotlib, bokeh, numba, pandas y sklearn.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pyday"></category><category term="sympy"></category><category term="numpy"></category><category term="scipy"></category><category term="matplotlib"></category><category term="bokeh"></category><category term="numba"></category><category term="pandas"></category><category term="sklearn"></category></entry><entry><title>Introduction to large scale data analytics and interactive visualization</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-es-2014/introduction-to-large-scale-data-analytics-and-interactive-visualization.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Christine Doig</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-04-06:pycon-es-2014/introduction-to-large-scale-data-analytics-and-interactive-visualization.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;NumPy, Pandas y Matplotlib, entre otros, han revolucionado el procesamiento, manipulación y visualización de datos en Python. ¿Pero, qué hacemos cuando nuestro dataset es demasiado grande para caber en la memoria de nuestro ordenador? ¿Usar una base de datos como Postgres o MongoDB, almacenar en disco con PyTables o BColz, o usar sistemas distribuidos como Hadoop o Spark?Cada una de estas opciones tiene sus ventajas e inconvenientes. Aprender cada una de estas herramientas consume tiempo que podría estar empleándose en el análisis de los datos en sí. La librería Blaze ofrece una interfaz común para una variedad de backends y abstracciones para el procesamiento y la migración de datos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Por otro lado, ¿cómo visualizamos nuestro dataset cuando tenemos más individuos que píxeles tiene nuestra pantalla? Bokeh es una librería para la visualización interactiva de datos en el navegador al estilo de D3.js en Python, que incluye la funcionalidad de Abstract Rendering para estos casos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La charla consistirá en una introducción al análisis y visualización de large datasets, cómo las librerías Blaze and Bokeh nos pueden facilitar el trabajo y un ejemplo práctico con un dataset de tweets.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Blaze"></category><category term="Bokeh"></category></entry><entry><title>Taller - Introducción a visualizaciones interactivas con Bokeh</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/pycon-es-2015/taller-introduccion-a-visualizaciones-interactivas-con-bokeh.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-02-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-02-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alejandro Vidal</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2016-02-02:pycon-es-2015/taller-introduccion-a-visualizaciones-interactivas-con-bokeh.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bokeh ( &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://bokeh.pydata.org/en/latest/"&gt;http://bokeh.pydata.org/en/latest/&lt;/a&gt; ) es una librería de visualización de datos con una interfaz concisa y elegante que permite la construcción de gráficos preparados para la web y con interactividad out-of-the-box y sencilla.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diseña avanzados dashboards en Python para un navegador web sin escribir ni una línea de código de Javascript (pero si quieres puedes ;P)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interactividad cliente-side, cliente-servidor, streaming, big data... Simplemente Bokeh! :)&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="workshop"></category><category term="Bokeh"></category></entry><entry><title>Bokeh for Data Storytelling</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/euroscipy-2015/bokeh-for-data-storytelling.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Bryan Van de Ven</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2015-10-05:euroscipy-2015/bokeh-for-data-storytelling.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Bokeh visualization library (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://bokeh.pydata.org"&gt;http://bokeh.pydata.org&lt;/a&gt;) has grown into a large, successful open source project. This talk will describe Bokeh and show how it can enable domain experts to easily create novel and powerful visualizations that extract insight from remote, possibly large data sets, to be published to the web for others to explore and interact with.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="bokeh"></category></entry><entry><title>Bokeh: Interactive Visualizations in the Browser</title><link href="http://pyvideo.org/scipy-2014/bokeh-interactive-visualizations-in-the-browser.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Bryan Van de Ven</name></author><id>tag:pyvideo.org,2014-07-09:scipy-2014/bokeh-interactive-visualizations-in-the-browser.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bokeh is a Python visualization library for large datasets that natively
uses the latest web technologies. Its goal is to provide concise
construction of novel graphics, while delivering high-performance
interactivity over large data to thin clients. This talk will cover the
motivation and architecture behind Bokeh, demonstrate interesting uses
and capability, and discuss future plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With support from the DARPA XDATA Initiative, and contributions from
community members, the Bokeh visualization library
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://bokeh.pydata.org"&gt;http://bokeh.pydata.org&lt;/a&gt;) has grown into a large, successful open source
project with heavy interest and following on GitHub
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/ContinuumIO/bokeh"&gt;https://github.com/ContinuumIO/bokeh&lt;/a&gt;). The principal goals of Bokeh are
to provide capability to developers and domain experts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;easily create novel and powerful visualizations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;that extract insight from remote, possibly large data sets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;published to the web for others to explore and interact&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will describe how the architecture of Bokeh enables these
goals, and demonstrate how it can be leveraged by anyone using python
for analysis to visualize and present their work. We will talk about
current development and future plans, including a brief discussion of
Joseph Cottam's exciting academic work on abstract rendering for large
data sets that is going into Bokeh
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/JosephCottam/AbstractRendering"&gt;https://github.com/JosephCottam/AbstractRendering&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="bokeh"></category><category term="vis"></category></entry></feed>